<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-05-24T19:41:56+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/</id><title type="html">Norstone USA</title><subtitle>New dimensions in natural stone.</subtitle><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><entry><title type="html">An Ivory Comeback for the Summer of 2017</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/an-ivory-comeback-for-the-summer-of-2017/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An Ivory Comeback for the Summer of 2017" /><published>2017-05-23T11:58:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-23T11:58:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/an-ivory-comeback-for-the-summer-of-2017</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/an-ivory-comeback-for-the-summer-of-2017/">&lt;p&gt;Long a favorite of the Norstone team, our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/rock-panels/ivory/&quot;&gt;Ivory Blend&lt;/a&gt; color, which we have available in both our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/stacked-stone-cladding/&quot;&gt;Standard Series&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/thin-stone-veneer-panels/&quot;&gt;XL Series Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt;, was on the opposite side of the recent “grey” color trend dominating neutral design colors of the past couple years.  We’ve always described the Ivory as a “blended” color with ranges from whites / off whites, to creams / ivories, and including some yellows and golds.  We’ve been pleasantly surprised to hear from many clients during the Spring and early Summer months of 2017 on a renewed interest in this color with many projects already installed or in various stages of design and construction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About two years ago, we got the opportunity to view and photograph a residential project in Southwest Florida that masterfully used our Ivory Standard Series Rock Panel on the exterior facade, both front and rear, on a new construction project.  Let’s take a look at how stacked stone was used on this project and what makes it so special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/05/23/Ivory%20Stone%20Veneer%20-%20Fort%20Myers%20%20-%20Facade.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ivory Stacked Stone Veneer on Exterior Residential Facade&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The front facade of this project features multiple columns where the outside corner unit worked perfectly to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stone-veneer-columns-norstone-classroom-series/&quot;&gt;wrap the columns in stone&lt;/a&gt;.  The entry way, which is strategically set further back from the street than the adjoining garage and opposite wing of the home, becomes the focal point of the exterior facade with the 1.5 story columns covered in stone taking center stage.  Smaller columns placed around the garage and other exterior parts of the home create a cohesive use of the stone.  An overall neutral color palette used on the smooth face stucco, trim, and metal roof complement the light color blend of the Ivory Rock Panel, and also serve as a great base for the window, door, and lighting fixture accents to pop off against.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/05/23/Ivory%20Stone%20Veneer%20-%20Fort%20Myers%20-%20Pool%20Feature.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ivory Stacked Stone Veneer Pool Waterline Tile&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming around to the rear of the house, the design team on this project also used the stone on a short accent wall on the pool deck as well as around a planter that dips down into the pool.  Since the Ivory color is a quartz based stone it is suitable to be used in wet and submerged environments, like the waterline tile seen here.  The light blended color range of Ivory also pairs extremely well with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/travertine-tiles-norstone-designer-series/&quot;&gt;travertine pavers and coping&lt;/a&gt;.  The short accent wall in the background might be a little hard to notice at first, but is worth taking note of because the space is incredibly well designed.  The skinny bamboo plantings do a great job of not blocking the stone at the lower level, and filling out and covering up the boring stucco wall above it.  The subtle up lighting makes sure the stacked stone accent wall stays within view even at nighttime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/05/23/Ivory%20Stone%20Veneer%20-%20Fort%20Myers%20%20-%20Outdoor%20Area-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ivory Stacked Stone Outdoor Living Space with fireplace and curved walls&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The showpiece of this home is most certainly this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-patios-designing-norstone-series/&quot;&gt;outdoor living space&lt;/a&gt;.  We love the subtle curves of the fireplace and bench seating areas as well as the overall color scheme, pairing the Ivory with gold and brown tones and the occasional orange and blue accent.  The curved stone work creates a great contrast with the normal flat look of stacked stone and this space embodies what a luxury outdoor living space should be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve got a stacked stone project to do this summer and are a little bored with the grey and black color range, our advice is to give Ivory a try.  We look forward to seeing what projects our customers complete during the Spring and Summer of 2017 and hope a few of you give Ivory a try!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Long a favorite of the Norstone team, our Ivory Blend color, which we have available in both our Standard Series and XL Series Rock Panels, was on the opposite side of the recent “grey” color trend dominating neutral design colors of the past couple years. We’ve always described the Ivory as a “blended” color with ranges from whites / off whites, to creams / ivories, and including some yellows and golds. We’ve been pleasantly surprised to hear from many clients during the Spring and early Summer months of 2017 on a renewed interest in this color with many projects already installed or in various stages of design and construction.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2017/05/23/Ivory%20Stone%20Veneer%20-%20Fort%20Myers%20%20-%20Outdoor%20Area.png%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Residential%20Ivory%20Stacked%20Stone%20Outdoor%20Living%20Space%20in%20Fort%20Myers,%20FL%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Residential%20Outdoor%20Living%20Space%20in%20Fort%20Myers,%20FL%20using%20Ivory%20Stacked%20Stone%20on%20a%20fireplace%20and%20curved%20walls%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Install a Flat Screen TV on a Stacked Stone Wall</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-install-a-flat-screen-tv-on-a-stacked-stone-wall/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Install a Flat Screen TV on a Stacked Stone Wall" /><published>2017-05-17T13:10:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-17T13:10:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-install-a-flat-screen-tv-on-a-stacked-stone-wall</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-install-a-flat-screen-tv-on-a-stacked-stone-wall/">&lt;p&gt;Over the years many of our customers have completed amazing feature walls using our stacked stone &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/&quot;&gt;rock panel products&lt;/a&gt;, and on quite a few of those feature walls they choose to hang a flat screen TV.  When we first started making our products TVs weren’t flat and definitely didn’t get hung on a wall, but as technology evolved and our customers pushed the design limits of their entertainment space the question about how to hang a flat screen tv on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-industry-series-what-is-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;stacked stone wall&lt;/a&gt; was one we needed to answer.  Here’s a quick “how to” guide for hanging a flat screen TV on a stacked stone wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-1-determine-the-scope-of-the-project&quot;&gt;Step 1: Determine the Scope of the Project&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever hanging a TV on a wall you’ll need to consider a few things including the locations of electrical and cable outlets.  Before you install anything it makes sense to understand if any of these services need moved, or perhaps a low voltage chaise installed in your wall cavity to allow for the proper hook ups in the location of the new unit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-2-prepare-the-substrate-for-stacked-stone&quot;&gt;Step 2: Prepare the Substrate for Stacked Stone&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most often this involves covering existing drywall with cement board, or if you are already at open wall studs, the cement board can be directly attached to the studs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/05/17/Flat%20Screen%20TV%20installed%20on%20Stacked%20Stone%20Wall%20-%20Installing%20Cement%20Board.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Flat Screen TV installed on Stacked Stone Wall - Installing Cement Board&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-3-select-the-tv-mount-and-check-for-clearance-on-the-wall&quot;&gt;Step 3: Select the TV Mount and Check for Clearance on the Wall&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wall mounts are readily available now through online retailers or brick and mortar electronic stores.  Be sure to select a mount that is properly sized for the television.  In this step it is also a good idea to check the clearance on your mount against the wall that will soon have stone on it.  Allow for at least 2” of stone and setting bed, and make sure you still have clearance to hang the TV on the mount without issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-4-install-the-tv-mount&quot;&gt;Step 4: Install the TV Mount&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the manufacturer’ directions, install the wall mount directly onto the cement board, making sure the screws being used are of sufficient length to reach into the studs.  Depending on the size of television and spacing of the wall studs, it might be a good idea to attach a few 1”x4”s to the wall, making sure these are firmly anchored into the studs, which will allow you more flexibility to place your mount exactly where you want it and attach it to the 1”x4”s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-5-protect-the-mount-and-install-the-stacked-stone&quot;&gt;Step 5: Protect the Mount and Install the Stacked Stone&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use painters or masking tape and some plastic sheeting to cover up the wall mount during installation of the stacked stone.  Install the stacked stone using a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/what-is-the-difference-between-different-types-of-thinset-and-what-s-the-best-thinset-for-stacked-stone-installations/&quot;&gt;polymer modified thinset &lt;/a&gt;and making the appropriate cuts around the mount.  It’s a good idea to save some extra stone in a closet or attic such that if you ever decide to take the TV down from the wall, you can remove the mount and go back and fill in the gap with stone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/05/17/Flat%20Screen%20TV%20installed%20on%20Stacked%20Stone%20Wall%20-%20Installing%20Stone.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Flat Screen TV installed on Stacked Stone Wall - Installing Stone&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-6-install-the-tv-mount-hang-on-the-wall-and-hook-up-connections&quot;&gt;Step 6: Install the TV Mount, Hang on the Wall and Hook Up Connections&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the stacked stone installation is complete, install the TV side of the wall mount on the TV unit itself and hang the entire unit on the wall.  A couple extra sets of hands can help a lot in this step by helping guide the TV into place and plugging in / managing the cords.  Most wall mounts will make a distinctive click when the unit is secured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-7-clean-up--enjoy&quot;&gt;Step 7: Clean Up &amp;amp; Enjoy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zip ties are a handy tool for managing excess length on any electrical or low voltage cables, so make sure that any excess length is tucked up nice and neat behind the TV. Finally, enjoy your new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/natural-stone-feature-walls/&quot;&gt;stacked stone media wall&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/05/17/Flat%20Screen%20TV%20installed%20on%20Stacked%20Stone%20Wall%20-%20Living%20Room.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Flat Screen TV installed on Stacked Stone Wall - Living Room&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In retrofit situations, where you already have stacked stone on a wall or fireplace and you’re wanting to come back and hang a tv over it, our first recommendation is to always see if a small portion of the stone can be cut or chipped out of the existing installation to create a flat surface to mount the bracket to.  It might be possible with a lot of patience and some sturdy shims to try and drill through the stone, and shim the bracket out on the face of an irregular surface like stacked stone.  If attempting a retrofit installation of that nature, its very important that a direct mechanical bond is made into the wall stud to make sure the TV stays safe on the wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a combined 40+ years experience in the stone industry our technical team is here to answer any questions you might have or troubleshoot anything unique to your project.  Call or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/contact-us/&quot;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt; today!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Over the years many of our customers have completed amazing feature walls using our stacked stone rock panel products, and on quite a few of those feature walls they choose to hang a flat screen TV. When we first started making our products TVs weren’t flat and definitely didn’t get hung on a wall, but as technology evolved and our customers pushed the design limits of their entertainment space the question about how to hang a flat screen tv on a stacked stone wall was one we needed to answer. Here’s a quick “how to” guide for hanging a flat screen TV on a stacked stone wall.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2017/05/17/Flat%20Screen%20TVs%20installed%20on%20Stacked%20Stone%20Wall%20-%20Casino.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Flat%20Screen%20TVs%20installed%20on%20Stacked%20Stone%20Wall%20-%20Casino%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Flat%20Screen%20TVs%20installed%20on%20Stacked%20Stone%20Wall%20in%20a%20Casino%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Study Surrounded by Beauty in this Downtown Philadelphia University Student Housing Lounge</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/study-surrounded-by-beauty-in-this-downtown-philadelphia-university-student-housing-lounge/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Study Surrounded by Beauty in this Downtown Philadelphia University Student Housing Lounge" /><published>2017-05-08T14:47:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-08T14:47:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/study-surrounded-by-beauty-in-this-downtown-philadelphia-university-student-housing-lounge</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/study-surrounded-by-beauty-in-this-downtown-philadelphia-university-student-housing-lounge/">&lt;p&gt;The beginning of May brings with it graduations across the country, filled with young people ready to take on the world.  Fond memories of our own university life were relived last fall when the Norstone team visited this cool installation at Drexel University featuring a large &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/fireplace/&quot;&gt;two sided fireplace&lt;/a&gt; adorned with our Ebony Basalt Interlocking Tile.  Having worked extensively with the design firm out of Austin, TX on this project, it was great to see our work come full circle from the initial sampling, design, bidding and construction, to now installed and being used and enjoyed by the students lucky enough to call this housing complex home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/05/08/Ebony%20Basalt%20Interlocking%20Tile%20Drexel%20University%20-%20Lobby%20View.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ebony Basalt Interlocking Tile Drexel University - Lobby View&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Situated in downtown Philadelphia, just across the Schuylkill River from Center City, this recently completed student housing tower feels a lot more like an upscale apartment complex in any major metropolitan area than what many of us would traditionally think of as a dormitory.  With numerous cafes and eateries within walking distance, and a clean exterior facade of glass and stonework, the lobby opens up beyond the check in desk to a lounge area with the two sided &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-trends-when-it-comes-to-stone-smooth-is-in/&quot;&gt;smooth basalt stone&lt;/a&gt; fireplace serving as both a focal point as well as a natural divider of the open space.  It’s hard to pull your eye away from the gas fireplace – at a long and skinny six feet in length this unit puts out a lot of attractive flames, the movement of which automatically becomes the focal point of the entire lobby area.  This space also holds a billiards area with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-school-pairing-lighting-fixtures-with-stone-veneer-for-amazing-results/&quot;&gt;modern lighting fixture&lt;/a&gt; and plenty of open seating option to either be social, or put your earbuds in and get some studying done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/05/08/Ebony%20Basalt%20Interlocking%20Tile%20Drexel%20University%20-%20See%20Though%20Fireplace.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ebony Basalt Interlocking Tile Drexel University - See Though Fireplace&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The opposite side of the fireplace is a sunken lounge with conversational style seating.  The design team did a fantastic job of pairing the clean geometric lines of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/modern-wall-tile/&quot;&gt;basalt interlocking tile&lt;/a&gt; used on the fireplace with modern furniture and linear accents.  From this side, the fireplace is really the focus of the space, and does a great job commanding your attention.  From the unique twin cut outs on either side, to the large TV, to the modern and eye catching linear gas see through fireplace, this project packs a lot of punch in a small area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/05/08/Ebony%20Basalt%20Interlocking%20Tile%20Drexel%20University%20-%20Gas%20Fireplace.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ebony Basalt Interlocking Tile Drexel University - Gas Fireplace&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things we like the most about this product is the subtle texture that it creates on the wall.  This view of the fireplace, taken to show some of the light coming in from the street level floor to ceiling windows shows some of that texture.  This product creates movement with its interlocking pattern, calibrated color variation, and just enough dimensionality to look really outstanding on a wall.  That dimensionality can be hard to detect in a photo, especially taken straight on, which is why we like this image so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/05/08/Ebony%20Basalt%20Interlocking%20Tile%20Drexel%20University%20-%20Bold%20Color%20Accents.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ebony Basalt Interlocking Tile Drexel University - Bold Color Accents&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One final thing that we enjoy about this project is the design team’s liberal stance on using color.  While the dark ebony color of the basalt interlocking tile goes well with the grey wood plank style flooring, and the predominantly grey base color of the walls, the use of in your face colors like the yellow accent wall deep pink pass throughs on either side of the fireplace bring a lot of life to the room.  Designing with those colors can be a challenge in a more conservative residential application, but the temporary and shared aspect of this student housing lounge makes them a perfect foil for the darker tones on the fireplace and flooring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This spring we salute the students who get to call this place home and hope that some of these bright young minds might have seen our tile, gained some inspiration, and will go out and do great things in this world.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">The beginning of May brings with it graduations across the country, filled with young people ready to take on the world. Fond memories of our own university life were relived last fall when the Norstone team visited this cool installation at Drexel University featuring a large two sided fireplace adorned with our Ebony Basalt Interlocking Tile. Having worked extensively with the design firm out of Austin, TX on this project, it was great to see our work come full circle from the initial sampling, design, bidding and construction, to now installed and being used and enjoyed by the students lucky enough to call this housing complex home.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2017/05/08/Ebony%20Basalt%20Interlocking%20Tile%20Drexel%20University%20-%204.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Ebony%20Bassalt%20Interlocking%20Fireplace%20Profile%20-%20Philadelphia%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Ebony%20Bassalt%20Interlocking%20Fireplace%20Profile%20-%20Philadelphia%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Install Mesh Backed Tile</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-install-mesh-backed-tile/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Install Mesh Backed Tile" /><published>2017-05-01T12:02:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-01T12:02:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-install-mesh-backed-tile</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-install-mesh-backed-tile/">&lt;p&gt;Mesh backed tile is a product both admired and despised in the industry.  Manufacturers and consumers love it because it allows for intricate tile patterns to be assembled and installed creating beautiful &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/mosaic-tile-backsplash-norstone-designer-series/&quot;&gt;tile mosaics&lt;/a&gt; that were previously only achieved via an artisan hand laying the pieces.  On the flip side, mesh backed tile can drive unqualified installers crazy if they don’t do simple things like plan accordingly for the pattern, or use quality setting materials and solid installation techniques to ensure a successful installation.  Here’s a detailed step by step guide on how to successfully install mesh backed tile like our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/modern-wall-tile/&quot;&gt;Basalt Interlocking Series&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-1-understanding-the-pattern&quot;&gt;Step 1: Understanding The Pattern&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understand the pattern of the mesh backed tile and how that pattern works with the space to be tiled.  This is a critical step so often overlooked!  Mesh backed tiles that don’t have a repeating pattern vertically can result in more waste.  A good way to know if your tile has a repeating pattern vertically is to put two tiles next to each other and flip one of them upside down.  If the horizontal lines of the two tiles still match up then your tiles have a repeating pattern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For mesh backed tiles without repeating patterns vertically, its important to plan for waste accordingly.  For example, if each of your tile units is 12” tall and you are are installing them on an 18” tall &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/backsplash-tile-designs-norstone-industy-series/&quot;&gt;backsplash&lt;/a&gt;, you’ll install one full unit, then cut the next unit in half to cover the 18”.  Since the half of the unit that was cut off does not match the pattern on the lower half it’s likely that the cut off piece will  end up as waste.  So it’s critical to understand your pattern and how that fits in the space to know how much to order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/05/01/Mesh%20Backed%20Tile%20-%20Norstone%20Basalt%20Interlocking.png&quot; alt=&quot;Mesh Backed Tile - Norstone Basalt Interlocking&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-2-get-the-right-substrate&quot;&gt;Step 2: Get the Right Substrate&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally speaking any vertical tile installation should be done on cement board or equivalent.  Drywall is not always designed to support the added weight of tile.  Cement board can always be layered over existing drywall to create a suitable tile substrate and any substrate for tiling should be rigid, level, plumb, and free of any contaminants that would prevent a good bond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-3-have-the-right-tools&quot;&gt;Step 3: Have the Right Tools&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few buckets for mixing and wipe down, a tile saw, paddle mixer, trowels, spacers, level, grout float, and a clean up sponge are all standard equipment for a successful mesh backed tile installation.  Depending on the type of tile being cut, for example stone vs glass vs porcelain, a different blade or other cutting tool might be needed for the cuts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/05/01/Tile%20Installation%20Tools.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Tile Installation Tools&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-4-use-the-proper-thinset&quot;&gt;Step 4: Use the Proper Thinset&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The manufacturer of the tile should provide guidelines for what type of thinset should be used for installation.  Generally speaking a thinset designed to meet or exceed ANSI 118.4 and ANSI 118.11 standards is suitable for most mesh backed tile installations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-5-mix-and-set&quot;&gt;Step 5: Mix and Set&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow the thinset manufacturer’s instructions on mixing the thinset to the desired consistency and don’t mix more thinset than can be used in approximately a 15 – 20 minute time period.  Trowel the thinset onto the wall and notch using the appropriate size groove for the tile size.  Depending on the size and weight of the tile, a coat or “back buttering” of the back of the tile with thinset might be recommended to ensure full adhesion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set the tiles onto the wall making sure to stay level and add spacers against hard surfaces like a floor, countertop, or windowsill to allow for a small expansion gap that can later be filled in with caulk.  When necessary use spaced between sheets or to maintain spacing on heavier individual tile strips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twist the tile during setting to make sure it sits firmly and fully into the thinset.  This is especially important for mesh backed tile to make sure the mesh in no way interferes with a solid bond between substrate and tile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clean any thinset off the face of the mesh backed tiles while installing to keep your job clean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/05/01/Mesh%20Backed%20Tile%20-%20Setting%20Tile%20In%20Thinset.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mesh Backed Tile - Setting Tile In Thinset&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-6-grout&quot;&gt;Step 6: Grout&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the thinset has cured, generally after 24 hours, mix the grout according to the manufacturer’s recommendation. Due to the thin lines of most mesh backed tiles, unsanded grout is commonly used, but check with the manufacturer of the tile for direction on what type of grout can be used.  Spread the grout using a rubber grout float and work the grout into the spaces making sure all the joints are filled.  After about 15-20 minutes, come back with a slightly damp sponge to remove the grout film from the surface of the tile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-7-ongoing-care&quot;&gt;Step 7: Ongoing Care&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow your tile manufacturer’s instructions for ongoing care, which might include sealing certain types of natural stone or a recommendation on types of cleaners to be used.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Mesh backed tile is a product both admired and despised in the industry. Manufacturers and consumers love it because it allows for intricate tile patterns to be assembled and installed creating beautiful tile mosaics that were previously only achieved via an artisan hand laying the pieces. On the flip side, mesh backed tile can drive unqualified installers crazy if they don’t do simple things like plan accordingly for the pattern, or use quality setting materials and solid installation techniques to ensure a successful installation. Here’s a detailed step by step guide on how to successfully install mesh backed tile like our Basalt Interlocking Series.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2017/05/01/Mesh%20Backed%20Tile%20-%20Kitchen%20Backsplash.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Mesh%20Backed%20Tile%20-%20Kitchen%20Backsplash%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Mesh%20Backed%20Tile%20-%20Kitchen%20Backsplash%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Sustainably Remodel Your Home</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-sustainably-remodel-your-home/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Sustainably Remodel Your Home" /><published>2017-04-17T14:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-17T14:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-sustainably-remodel-your-home</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-sustainably-remodel-your-home/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;environmental-impact-of-home-remodeling&quot;&gt;Environmental Impact of Home Remodeling&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you can’t wait to implement a new interior design style you’ve always dreamed of, or are getting ready to make more room for your growing family, the thought of remodeling your home can be incredibly thrilling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you walk through the steps of how to accomplish enhancing your living space however, it can also become overwhelming. When remodeling your home there are many things to consider such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What parts of your home do you love that you want to keep?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What should be nixed and started over from scratch?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you begin to research the vast amount of options for home remodeling, you will want to decide where sustainability falls into your remodeling priorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;positive-impacts-of-green-remodeling&quot;&gt;Positive Impacts of Green Remodeling&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By choosing to remodel, you have already made a green choice. Instead of building a home from scratch, remodeling allows you to reuse materials in your home that are already in place. According to Natural Life Magazine, buildings make up approximately 40 percent of the energy and materials used in the world. Remodeling your home with sustainability in mind will contribute to a positive impact on the world’s energy consumption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having an environmentally-friendly home will allow you to avoid many negative aspects of renovating, such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Hurting the environment with newly harvested and wasted materials&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Off-gassing of toxins&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Increasing the amount of construction and demolition waste and debris&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having an eco-friendly home can change the quality of life for you and your family in many drastic ways. Sustainable appliances will ultimately reduce the cost of bills thanks to their energy efficiency. According to the U.S. Green Building Council, the average household spends about $2,150 on energy bills, but sustainable houses have saved between 30-60 percent on those bills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt; “The average household spends about $2,150 on energy bills, but sustainable houses have saved 30-60 percent on those bills.” &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Sustainable%20Home%20Remodel%20Ideas%20-%20Atlanta%20Kitchen.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sustainable Home Remodel Ideas - Atlanta Kitchen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are even incentives offered by local, state, and federal agencies for going green in your lifestyle. Windows, doors, roofing, insulation, and HVAC are all items of a home remodel that are subject to tax credits. Local utility providers sometimes offer rebates for green upgrades as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;choose-refreshing-over-replacing&quot;&gt;Choose refreshing over replacing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of replacing all of the materials in your home, remodeling in a sustainable way by reusing materials can also save you money. Recycling is a huge aspect of living a green lifestyle. Repurposing items and materials prevents unnecessary, additional purchases for your home upgrades. Saving natural resources and reducing the emissions from the manufacturing and transportation of these materials does the environment a huge favor. Many green products and materials are also more durable and effective compared to non-sustainable products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-to-know-before-your-green-home-remodel&quot;&gt;What to Know before Your Green Home Remodel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you dive into remodeling and creating your dream eco-friendly living space, investigate what you already have in your home that may comply with sustainable living.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your home may already be more sustainable than you think; check its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epcregister.com/&quot;&gt;Energy Performance Certificate&lt;/a&gt; (EPC) to tell what you are working with when remodeling your home. This certificate will provide insight into your house’s energy use and carbon dioxide emissions. The grading
system goes from “A”, the most energy-efficient, to “G” as the least, and gives homeowners  an idea of how green their home really is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-green-around-your-house&quot;&gt;What’s Green Around Your House&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Insulation is generally not green unless you specifically seek the use of sustainable materials, such as recycled resources. Making an investment in insulating your home however, can actually save you money on your power bill. Since energy is wasted in homes that are poorly insulated, this energy-efficient upgrade is good for your wallet and the environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Windows are another aspect of your home to look at updating. Double-glazed windows are sustainable and energy efficient. Wood-framed windows are also a sustainable option, as opposed to uPVC (unplasticized polyvinyl chloride) or metal. They insulate better, are easier to repair, and last far longer than other window framing options. UPVC, commonly used to frame domestic windows, emits harsh toxins into the air, making wooden frames in your home a more sustainable alternative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-not-green&quot;&gt;What’s Not Green&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A common energy-guzzling household item is often the air purifier. They are designed to clean the air and decrease odors, but produce ozone at a very minor level. Ozone is what is found in upper levels of the atmosphere and is what protects the world from ultraviolet (UV) rays, but breathing in this ozone can cause respiratory issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carpeting and rugs are not green items to have in your home, as they harvest toxins like formaldehyde and later release it into the air. The glue used to install carpet also creates breathable toxins that harm human health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;deconstruct-instead-of-demolish&quot;&gt;Deconstruct Instead of Demolish&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Demolition has an immense, negative impact on the environment due to material waste. Before remodeling your home, think strategically about what to deconstruct and what items to keep. Thinking sustainably ahead of time can save you money by minimizing your long list of materials to buy and reduce waste. Walk through your home and see what you can re-use. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-school-pairing-lighting-fixtures-with-stone-veneer-for-amazing-results/&quot;&gt;Light fixtures&lt;/a&gt;, molding, cabinets, and even doors can be repurposed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;starting-small&quot;&gt;Starting Small&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If after doing your research you realize that you just can’t sustainably remodel your entire house at the moment, think about it in phases. If you want to start with running a more efficient household, focus on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Energy-efficient appliances&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;On-demand water heaters&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;High-efficiency insulation&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Solar technology&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step of your green remodel can tackle things like using:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Sustainably harvested woods&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Reclaimed lumber for system rebuilding&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Reclaimed fixtures&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Rainwater collection as part of your home plumbing system&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you love the idea of renovating your home to be more energy efficient, but can’t take on a full house remodel, think about remodeling on a room-by-room basis. It may feel more realistic to take on the upgrading of kitchen appliances to be more sustainable, instead of picturing all of the things in your home that need to be addressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When thinking about starting small, you can also take a step back and conceptualize how much space you actually need in your home. If you have a room that doesn’t get much use, you can either reduce your overall square footage or repurpose it into a space that would be further enjoyed. Smaller living spaces are ultimately more affordable, and have less negative impact on the environment by using less materials and emitting less toxins into the air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another idea that is mindful of space is to double up on the purposes of your rooms. You can easily add a washer and dryer to a kitchen or bedroom in a discreet way, or even into a hallway or a closet. Open-concept homes often have one large room that serves as the kitchen area, living room, and dining room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Sustainable%20Home%20Remodel%20Ideas%20-%20Dallas%20Fireplace-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sustainable Home Remodel Ideas - Dallas Stone Fireplace&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;room-by-room&quot;&gt;Room by Room&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-kitchen&quot;&gt;The Kitchen&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An eco-friendly kitchen possesses a design that embodies healthy living as well as energy efficiency. Nontoxic materials used in the kitchen are central to having a sustainable kitchen as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From cabinetry to flooring, these products often have added urea formaldehyde, which emits gases and endangers healthy living. Glue, sealant, paint, and coating also have toxins that should be avoided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When designing your kitchen, it is advised to go for more classic looks, rather than adhering to today’s trends. Not only will it cost you money to replace out-of-style colors and countertops, but it also fuels waste buildup by frequently ripping out and replacing these materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/backsplash/&quot;&gt;stone backsplash&lt;/a&gt; is a favorite final touch for many homeowners. This can be one of the most sustainable elements in your green kitchen. Norstone Rock Panels are commonly used for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/stacked-stone-cladding/&quot;&gt;stacked stone&lt;/a&gt; backsplashes as they have one of the most durable finishes, and use a natural stone sealer. When combined with chic glass in a modern kitchen, stacked stone really stands out in kitchen design.&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Sustainable%20Home%20Remodel%20Ideas%20-%20Orlando%20Backsplash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sustainable Home Remodel Ideas - Orlando Backsplash&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;energy-efficient-appliances&quot;&gt;Energy-Efficient Appliances&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One easy way to have confidence that your appliances are sustainable is to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.energystar.gov/&quot;&gt;Energy Star&lt;/a&gt;®, the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency’s defining, voluntary program in the energy efficiency movement. Since 1992, Energy Star has served as a voluntary labeling program that allows consumers to identify and use energy-efficient appliances. In fact, the increase in purchases of Energy Star appliances has reduced greenhouse gas emissions by 2.5 billion tons since its inception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro Tip:&lt;/strong&gt;In addition to having only the most sustainable appliances in your kitchen, it will also make a difference where you place them. Choose to locate your refrigerator in an area of your kitchen where it will not be exposed to direct sunlight to optimize its energy-saving capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bathrooms&quot;&gt;Bathrooms&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may be surprised to find out that 27 percent of household water is used in toilets. Installing and maintaining efficient water and plumbing systems are critical factors to consider when sustainably remodeling your bathroom. Your shower and sink faucets can also be swapped out with low-flow devices in order to save on water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to conserve more water, low-volume and dual-flush mechanism toilets are becoming more popular as well. As for sinks, know what materials are safe to use in your green bathroom.
Natural ceramic and nontoxic cement are popular options for hardware and sink basins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;choosing-materials&quot;&gt;Choosing Materials&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing what you are purchasing when it comes to remodeling your home is arguably the most challenging aspect. Homeowners need to know what to look for when purchasing products, materials, and appliances. Keep in mind that there are currently no EPA regulations around terms like “natural”, “organic”, or “sustainable”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt; “Keep in mind that there are currently no EPA regulations around terms like ‘natural’, ‘organic’, or ‘sustainable’.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All sustainable products are not created equal. Like Energy Star, there are certifications that indicate a level of sustainability, such as the Greenguard certification. This will help optimize the indoor air quality of your home. The best way to do this is to look for materials that will not emit toxic chemicals into the air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avoid volatile organic compounds (VOCs), since due to off-gassing; they greatly contribute to air pollution. For some, this may be difficult to prioritize in your remodel because it is intangible. However, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/indoor-air-quality-iaq/volatile-organic-compounds-impact-indoor-air-quality#Health_Effects&quot;&gt;according to the EPA&lt;/a&gt;, VOCs pose long-term health problems like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;eye, nose, and throat irritation&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;headaches, loss of coordination, and nausea&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;damage to liver, kidney, and central nervous system&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;some organics can cause cancer in animals and humans&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, green home products are more durable and effective than man-made products. For instance, a wool rug will outlive a synthetic rug by about 45 years. In the same manner, natural linoleum lasts twice as long as vinyl flooring. Granite is one of the most popular countertop materials since it can last for generations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to countertops, backsplashes, wall space, and flooring, natural stone is hard to beat. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/what-makes-norstone-different-a-lot/&quot;&gt;Norstone Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt; use natural stone products, such as quartz, quartzite sedimentary stone, and lava stone for Rock Panels. The durability and sustainable installation process of these natural stone products make them a top option for remodeling materials.&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Sustainable%20Home%20Remodel%20Ideas%20-%20San%20Francisco%20Courtyard.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sustainable Home Remodel Ideas - San Francisco Courtyard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;eco-friendly-painting&quot;&gt;Eco-Friendly Painting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two aspects that can make painting eco-friendly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The types of paint you select&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How you dispose of your paint waste&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Water-based paint with natural pigments is as close to all-natural paint as you can get. Most conventional paint types for homes are oil-based. The production of oil-based paint, however, is less energy efficient. Oftentimes, water-based paint with natural pigments has a smoother finish as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Water-based paints also contain low or no levels of VOCs. These toxins are especially dangerous in paint because they evaporate during the drying process, can contribute to indoor air contamination, and leave the unpleasant smell that is associated with painting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can generally find water-based paint with the same durability and performance of conventional paint. Being based from water, the paint is also safer to use overall. No more
scrubbing your arms and legs for days after painting a room – water-based paint rinses off with soap and water. You’ll also find yourself having to repaint less often because of the acrylic technology many water-based paints use, allowing for longer-lasting life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you have selected your water-based paint and the painting is done, it is critical that paint cans and extra paint are not just thrown away or poured down a sink drain. Waste disposal of this type will be drained into local streams and could potentially pollute ponds.
To properly dispose of paint in an eco-friendly manner, turn it into solid waste. Leave the paint can open to harden it, or mix it with hardening agents, such as cat litter, to speed up the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;solar-paneling-and-solar-energy&quot;&gt;Solar Paneling and Solar Energy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solar panel systems create electricity without producing global warming pollution and provide many benefits to your home and the environment. The biggest benefit is that it decreases your home’s contribution to global warming, one of the biggest environmental threats to the survival of human society and the world as we know it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is also extremely cost efficient for society, saving billions of dollars as more homeowners choose to install it on their homes. The average savings over 20 years for Americans who install solar panels to their home in 2011 is projected to be just over $20,000.
Other uses of solar energy include light tubes for day lighting, allowing you to bring in more light therefore cutting back on the need for artificial lighting. An investment in solar light tubes is returned in five to seven years, but comes with the added benefit of having much more daylight in your home. Though the design of skylights is different, the intent is similar to that of solar light tubes, as your energy is being used more efficiently for more lighting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solar technology can also be used for heating your water. Buying solar hot water panels for your home heats the water you use in your home and your pool. In some countries, these hot water panels are commonly adopted. In the U.S., government incentives are available to help homeowners afford solar thermal panels. On average, hot water panels decrease water bills by 50 to 80 percent and have a financial payback in 6 to 10 years.
If you find your lighting needs frequently changing, you can use solar landscape and patio lighting. They’re oftentimes found on lawns, but they are easy to relocate.
Grants and tax incentives are made available by organizations like the Energy Investment Tax Credit, known also as the Solar Investment Tax Credit, providing a $30 federal tax credit for residential solar systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;green-savvy-experts&quot;&gt;Green-Savvy Experts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless you live in a green community where there are networks upon networks of sustainable contractors for remodeling homes, it is wise to do your own research to be able to offer suggestions on eco-friendly materials when it comes to your remodel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that being said, do not feel discouraged, as there are countless designers that are fully informed and have a driving principle to make people’s homes more sustainable. In fact, nearly one third of builders say that more than 60 percent of their projects are on green remodeling. It is safe to say that for many builders and designers, it is an expectation to build in an eco-friendly way.&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Sustainable%20Home%20Remodel%20Ideas%20-%20Thinset%20Installation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sustainable Home Remodel Ideas - Thinset Installation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if some products say that they are “green” or “all natural”, they may not be completely free of toxins. It is imperative to enlist a designer who knows your need to be green, and the extent that sustainability exists in the remodeling of a home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some sample questions that an environmentally-friendly designer should be able to answer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“What is your process to incorporate my needs into a successful kitchen design?”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“How are you positive that the selected design and new architecture of my home will last a lifetime?”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“What materials do you find to be more durable, and also do not emit toxins into the air?”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“What are some fads you are seeing that we should avoid when creating a green living space?”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being able to know what you want and how to describe it to the experts requires doing your own research. Articulating your needs and expectations are a must to be able to have your builder put your vision into motion. Visiting building supply stores to look into Energy Star appliances, recycled material options, and efficient lighting is a great way to start. You can also take tours of local green homes near you to scope out designs that match your dream home ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sustainability-on-a-budget&quot;&gt;Sustainability on a Budget&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contrary to popular belief, remodeling your home sustainably does not mean it has to be expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reclaimed-materials&quot;&gt;Reclaimed Materials&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying reclaimed materials, like wood, is an environmentally-friendly choice. Reclaimed resources are becoming more popular among home renovators. Reclaimed wood, for example, is a durable and sustainable choice for countertops, flooring, and walls. This saves not only time and energy, but money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Refacing instead of replacing will also save you money. Find ways to salvage what is already yours to help your budget remain conservative. This remodeling strategy allows for creativity, as one piece in your laundry room may really bring out your new design in your remodeled kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;shop-local&quot;&gt;Shop Local&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shopping locally will allow you to save on shipping. Though shipping may not be the first cost that comes to mind, having green materials shipped across the country, or the world, can quickly add up. By searching locally for handmade materials, you will save on resources and materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying pre-owned materials is another general way to cut renovation costs. There are many local sources for used hardware, plumbing, cabinetry, appliances, and countertops. Salvaged building supply stores are growing and becoming more popular all over the country, as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sources:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.motherearthnews.com/green-homes/home-renovation-impact-environment-zbcz1507&quot;&gt;Mother Earth News: Guide to Living Wisely (Website)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://elemental.green/the-top-10-myths-about-green-home-remodeling/&quot;&gt;The Top 10 Myths About Green Home Remodeling (2017) by Elemental Green&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://livegreen.recyclebank.com/the-list-the-5-least-green-items-in-your-home&quot;&gt;The List: The 5 Least Green Items in Your Home (2014) by Recycle Bank (Website)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/&quot;&gt;Norstone: New Dimensions in Natural Stone (2017) (Website)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://freshome.com/2012/10/25/10-eco-friendly-ways-to-renovate-your-home/&quot;&gt;10 Eco-Friendly Ways to Design Your Home (2012) by Freshome (Website)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thisoldhouse.com/ideas/planning-green-remodel&quot;&gt;Planning a Green Remodel (2017) by This Old House (Website)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.greenguard.com/&quot;&gt;Green Guard: The FIrst Aid People (2017) (Website)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/finance/property/green/7939220/Green-property-George-Clarkes-top-20-ways-to-make-your-home-eco-friendly.html&quot;&gt;Green Property: George Clarke’s Top 20 Ways to Make Your Home Eco-Friendly (2010) by The Telegraph Media Group Limited (Website)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bostonglobe.com/magazine/2014/09/03/ideas-for-environmentally-friendly-kitchen/LattGrhI5mraIy1WtwP29O/story.html&quot;&gt;25 Ideas for an Environmentally Friendly Kitchen (2014) by The Boston Globe (Website)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.energystar.gov/&quot;&gt;Energy Star: The Simple Choice for Energy Efficiency (Website)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.treehugger.com/htgg/how-to-go-green-bathroom-renovation.html&quot;&gt;How to Go Green: Bathroom Renovation (2007) by Treehugger: The Way Forward Is Here (Website)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paintquality.com/en/understanding-paint/sustainability&quot;&gt;Sustainability and Paint by Paint Quality Institute (Website)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cleantechnica.com/2013/10/08/advantages-disadvantages-solar-power/&quot;&gt;Advantages and Disadvantages of Solar Power (2013) by Clean Technica (Website)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Environmental Impact of Home Remodeling</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/assets/images/Sustainable%20Home%20Remodel%20Ideas%20-%20San%20Francisco%20Courtyard%20Project.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Sustainable%20Home%20Remodel%20Ideas%20-%20San%20Francisco%20Courtyard%20Project%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Sustainable%20Home%20Remodel%20Ideas%20-%20San%20Francisco%20Courtyard%20Project%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Everything Tile &amp;amp; Stone at Coverings in Orlando</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/everything-tile-stone-at-coverings-in-orlando/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Everything Tile &amp; Stone at Coverings in Orlando" /><published>2017-04-13T14:22:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-13T14:22:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/everything-tile-stone-at-coverings-in-orlando</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/everything-tile-stone-at-coverings-in-orlando/">&lt;p&gt;Every year our industry gathers for a conference focused on the tile and stone industry called Coverings.  This year the show was close to home in at the Orange County Convention Center in Orlando, FL and our whole team got an opportunity to check out the show, talk to and network with many of our wholesale customers, and see 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-trends-when-it-comes-to-stone-smooth-is-in/&quot;&gt;what’s trending in the tile and stone industry&lt;/a&gt;.  Here are some of our highlights from the past week.&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Coverings%20Floor%20Shoot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Coverings Stone &amp;amp; Tile Show Exhibition Hall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The show started on Tuesday morning and the leadership team of Norstone USA was on it early, putting in some miles back and forth through the exhibit hall in search of new and interesting products.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/real-stone-vs-faux-norstone-industry-series/&quot;&gt;Since we focus exclusively on natural stone&lt;/a&gt;, we spent most of our time around the perimeter of the exhibition hall since the center is dominated by the Italian, Spanish, and North American porcelain and ceramic tile manufacturers.  We visited with many manufacturers from Turkey, Egypt and various parts of Asia, getting lots of great ideas for products that the market might be interested in.  We also spent some time with the setting materials manufacturer’s at the show, learning all about the latest advancements to 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/what-is-the-difference-between-different-types-of-thinset-and-what-s-the-best-thinset-for-stacked-stone-installations/&quot;&gt;tile thinset&lt;/a&gt; and how that can improve the installation techniques of our products.&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/D&amp;amp;B%20Tile%20Coverings%20Group.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;D&amp;amp;B Tile trip to Coverings Stone &amp;amp; Tile 2017&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wednesday we spent most of the day with one of our amazing distributor partners, D&amp;amp;B Tile.  Whenever Coverings is in Orlando, D&amp;amp;B sponsors a bus trip from their headquarters in South Florida to the show for the day.  Many of their best customers, ranging from top level architects and designers based in Miami to tile contractors who buy all their material through D&amp;amp;B take advantage of this trip.  We sponsored a lunch where we got a chance to speak with everyone who came on the trip about our 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/&quot;&gt;products&lt;/a&gt;, answer any questions, and get some great face time in with the good folks at D&amp;amp;B who have supported our product day in and day out for over a decade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Thursday the Norstone team logged a few more miles pounding the convention center floor in search of new products and design trends to inspire our own creativity and product development.  Along the way, we saw cool new products in the tile industry, like a wet saw that doesn’t use any water, and large format tiles that were printed similar to thermofoil over foam that were so well made they were indistinguishable from standard porcelain or ceramic (yet far lighter!).&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Coverings%20Stone%20&amp;amp;%20Tile%20Orlando%202017%20-%20Italian%20Pavillion.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Coverings Stone &amp;amp; Tile Orlando 2017 Italian Pavillion&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finished out the show by sitting down with another tile distributor we do business with based in New Jersey and Pennsylvania.  This great family run business with 10+ locations has been open for over 60 years and as such, has seen first hand the ebbs and flow of this industry.  What was apparent to everyone that had spent time at Coverings this year was that the gap between tile manufacturers was getting smaller and smaller.  Years ago, there was a marked difference between what the high end innovative manufacturers in Italy and Spain were producing versus what you saw coming out of the parts of the world that are newer to selling tile in the North American market, like South America and Asia.  Now, there are so many good products in the market that it’s really more about the relationships you form with your customers.  At Norstone, we’ve always valued those relationships, and will continue to do so, whether its with our big whole customers or a homeowner we’re able to work with direct that has trusted part of the vision of their project to us.  In a crowded marketplace it truly is the little things that stand out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coverings 2018 will be in Atlanta, GA and the Norstone team looks forward to being there again to celebrate all that is tile and stone!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Every year our industry gathers for a conference focused on the tile and stone industry called Coverings. This year the show was close to home in at the Orange County Convention Center in Orlando, FL and our whole team got an opportunity to check out the show, talk to and network with many of our wholesale customers, and see what’s trending in the tile and stone industry. Here are some of our highlights from the past week.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/assets/images/Coverings%20Tile%20&amp;%20Stone%20Show%20Exhibition%20Hall.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Coverings%20Orlando%202017%20Tile%20&amp;%20Stone%20Show%20-%20Entrance%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Coverings%20Orlando%202017%20Tile%20&amp;%20Stone%20Show%20-%20Entrance%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Basalt Tile for a Multi Family Outdoor Living Space in Washington, D.C.</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/basalt-tile-for-a-multi-family-outdoor-living-space-in-washington-d-c/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Basalt Tile for a Multi Family Outdoor Living Space in Washington, D.C." /><published>2017-03-30T18:09:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-30T18:09:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/basalt-tile-for-a-multi-family-outdoor-living-space-in-washington-d-c</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/basalt-tile-for-a-multi-family-outdoor-living-space-in-washington-d-c/">&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Stone, whether it be in panels or tiles, has always been a favorite material for designers working on multifamily projects.  The obvious durability of the product makes sure the design stays looking crisp over time, which is especially important in multi family projects which tend to get a lot more usage than residential projects but might not have the same level of maintenance and upkeep budgeted as a commercial project.  We got the opportunity to work with the design team on this large multifamily projects located on the site of the former train depot between Alexandria and Arlington, VA.  Looking to target young professionals in the Metro D.C. Area, the design team was evoked a modern style and assembled amenities that would matter to the target audience.  Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/modern-wall-tile/grey/&quot;&gt;Ash Grey Basalt Interlocking Tiles&lt;/a&gt; were selected and installed in various places throughout the shared &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-patios-designing-norstone-series/&quot;&gt;outdoor living&lt;/a&gt; space.  Let's take a look at how the product was expertly used throughout these spaces and features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably the biggest eye catcher in this whole project is the low slung linear firepit which uses the stone on all four sides and a matching bluestone cap on top.  Flanked by comfortable Adirondack style chairs, the clean lines and 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-trends-when-it-comes-to-stone-smooth-is-in/&quot;&gt;smooth texture&lt;/a&gt; of the basalt tiles complement the modern look of this gas firepit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Grey%20Basalt%20Interlocking%20Tile%20-%20Landbay%20J%20-%20Washington%20DC%20-%20Firepit-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Grey Basalt Interlocking Tile - Landbay J - Washington DC - Firepit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just on the opposite side of the firepit is a cool multilevel water feature.  These two spaces are tied together by the use of similar materials, but provide that dynamic contrast, that good design often seeks, between the water and fire.  Equally adept in water, the grey color of the interlocking basalt tile darkens up when wet giving us some movement in color to reflect on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Grey%20Basalt%20Interlocking%20Tile%20-%20Landbay%20J%20-%20Washington%20DC%20-%20Outdoor%20Kitchen.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Grey Basalt Interlocking Tile - Landbay J - Washington DC - Outdoor Kitchen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next most prominent feature in this space is the large communal outdoor kitchen and grilling station.  With a commercial level grill and prep sink, this truly is an outdoor kitchen, and not a bring your own charcoal type of grill setup you’ll find in other places. The color of the solid surface countertop blends nicely with the grey tones of the basalt stone, which also contrast nicely with the prominent stainless steel grill and fixtures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Grey%20Basalt%20Interlocking%20Tile%20-%20Landbay%20J%20-%20Washington%20DC%20-%20Outdoor%20Living.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Grey Basalt Interlocking Tile - Landbay J - Washington DC - Outdoor Living&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prominent throughout the entire space is well selected outdoor furniture that adds to the design from both a style and color standpoint.  Stylistically, the modern bulky yet clean lined look of the furniture works well within the rest of the design, and the selected red upholstery featured throughout add an important element of color pop.  The red accents stand out against the grey of the basalt interlocking tile just enough to be bold but definitely not brash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Grey%20Basalt%20Interlocking%20Tile%20-%20Landbay%20J%20-%20Washington%20DC%20-%20Planter.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Grey Basalt Interlocking Tile - Landbay J - Washington DC - Planter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One last contrast we appreciate in this project is the use of the basalt interlocking tile on planter boxes throughout the space.  The one featured here, where the stone of the planter box goes right down into another planting bed is a great example of marrying up two contrasting design elements – the hardness and monotone color of the stone tile with the softness and earth tones of the plantings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Basalt Interlocking Tile product has proven to be a very versatile material choice in the hands of adept designers.  Creating great contrast, whether through color, shape or size, this 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-mosaics-norstone-design-series/&quot;&gt;mosaic tile&lt;/a&gt; product is an excellent choice for your next modern inspired project, indoors, outdoors, or anywhere in between.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Stone, whether it be in panels or tiles, has always been a favorite material for designers working on multifamily projects. The obvious durability of the product makes sure the design stays looking crisp over time, which is especially important in multi family projects which tend to get a lot more usage than residential projects but might not have the same level of maintenance and upkeep budgeted as a commercial project. We got the opportunity to work with the design team on this large multifamily projects located on the site of the former train depot between Alexandria and Arlington, VA. Looking to target young professionals in the Metro D.C. Area, the design team was evoked a modern style and assembled amenities that would matter to the target audience. Our Ash Grey Basalt Interlocking Tiles were selected and installed in various places throughout the shared outdoor living space. Let's take a look at how the product was expertly used throughout these spaces and features.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/assets/images/Grey%20Basalt%20Interlocking%20Tile%20-%20Landbay%20J%20-%20Washington%20DC%20-%20Firepit.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Basalt%20Interlocking%20Tile%20Outdoor%20Living%20Firepit%20&amp;%20Water%20Feature%20Washington,%20D.C.%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Basalt%20Interlocking%20Tile%20Outdoor%20Living%20Firepit%20&amp;%20Water%20Feature%20Washington,%20D.C.%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Outside the Box Stone Design Ideas For Your Next Remodel or New Build</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/outside-the-box-stone-design-ideas-for-your-next-remodel-or-new-build/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Outside the Box Stone Design Ideas For Your Next Remodel or New Build" /><published>2017-03-20T15:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-20T15:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/outside-the-box-stone-design-ideas-for-your-next-remodel-or-new-build</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/outside-the-box-stone-design-ideas-for-your-next-remodel-or-new-build/">&lt;p&gt;One of the things we love about our products is that over the years we’ve gotten to work with lots of amazing designers, as well as bunches of homeowners, who each have their own unique vision of what they’re trying to achieve with their project. The customer service and attention to detail we, and our amazing team of distributors and dealers, provide is something you simply don’t get when buying stone products through big box stores or discount flooring centers. The ones that are especially memorable are the clients that use the product in a new and totally unique way that even takes us by surprise! Stacked stone and stone veneer is always going to be a major design trend on our most popular projects like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/fireplace/&quot;&gt;fireplaces&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/backsplash/&quot;&gt;backsplashes&lt;/a&gt;, but these projects below, as well as many others, inspire us with their creative use of stone veneer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Stacked%20Stone%20Shower%20Wall%20-%20Denmark.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stacked Stone Shower Wall Denmark&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using stacked stone in a shower isn’t something we thought of until we got these amazing photos many years ago from a contemporary residence in Denmark. Our Charcoal Standard Series Rock Panels are featured in this large master bathroom and serve as an accent wall in a large walk in / doorless master shower. Still an incredibly unique project and application to this day, we’ve since worked with many clients who have installed stone veneer in shower and bath applications. Some of the key things we review with each client considering this type of application is the critical importance of waterproofing and the correct installation materials and techniques, the need to evacuate the hot and humid air from the room during and after shower use, and setting the right expectation that a highly textured product like stacked stone isn’t going to be maintenance free in an application such as this. The spa like look and feeling clients can achieve with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-bathrooms-designing-norstone-series/&quot;&gt;stacked stone bathroom&lt;/a&gt; makes it all worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Circular%20Stone%20Stairwell%20-%20Atlanta,%20GA.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Circular Stone Stairwell Atlanta, GA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another project that opened our eyes up to the possibilities of stacked stone was this awesome stair landing project a client of ours did in Atlanta in the mid 2000s. The design team behind this project wowed us by using the standard series rock panel in a vertical orientation (24” tall x 6” wide) which allowed the installers to bend it around the curve on this tight stairway landing. The sleek look of the white stacked stone, sets up beautifully against the black stairs and railing and modern art and fixtures in this space, and the vertical orientation of the panels works perfectly to maximize the height in this stairway making each trip up and down a memorable one for the lucky clients that call this place home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Stacked%20Stone%20Home%20Music%20Studio%20-%20Philadephia,%20PA.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stacked Stone Home Music Studio Philadephia, PA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This next project, a small guitar / music studio in a client’s basement, helped spark our interest in learning more about how a product like ours can benefit the acoustics of a space, and indirectly helped us work on one of our most beautiful projects to date, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/project/rockport/&quot;&gt;Rockport Concert Hall&lt;/a&gt;. As a stone veneer manufacturer we didn’t realize that the irregularity and high degree of texture, as well as the density of the stone itself, had major acoustic benefits by deflecting and absorbing sound waves. While this client was just looking for a cool looking place to jam out, we’ve since worked with both consumer and professional level audio studios on projects and look forward to seeing our products deflect and absorb more sounds waves in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Stone%20Veneer%20Circle%20Cut%20Out%20-%20Seychelles,%20Africa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stone Veneer Circular Cut Out Seychelles&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One last project that really stood out the first time we saw it completed was this amazing outdoor living space in the Seychelles, and island nation off the coast of Africa. While using stacked stone in an outdoor living space isn’t altogether unique, the design team’s inspiration to incorporate a large circular cut out in the wall, creating a “port hole” of sorts, creates its own visual interest in the space and doesn’t do anything to diminish the amazing view from this patio, while still maintaining privacy. The combination of the straight line geometry of the stone veneer and the curves of the circle complement each other instead of clashing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, there’s so much more to stone veneer than just fireplaces, and we hope this small collection of projects have inspired you to think of outside the box ways &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-industry-series-what-is-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;stacked stone&lt;/a&gt; can be incorporated into your next project. Our design experts would be glad to discuss turning your inspiration into reality - contact us to see what’s possible. In the meantime, stay creative and send us your favorite outside the box stone projects – we’d love to see them!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">One of the things we love about our products is that over the years we’ve gotten to work with lots of amazing designers, as well as bunches of homeowners, who each have their own unique vision of what they’re trying to achieve with their project. The customer service and attention to detail we, and our amazing team of distributors and dealers, provide is something you simply don’t get when buying stone products through big box stores or discount flooring centers. The ones that are especially memorable are the clients that use the product in a new and totally unique way that even takes us by surprise! Stacked stone and stone veneer is always going to be a major design trend on our most popular projects like fireplaces and backsplashes, but these projects below, as well as many others, inspire us with their creative use of stone veneer.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/assets/images/Charcoal%20Stone%20Tile%20Shower.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Charcoal%20Stone%20Tile%20Shower%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Charcoal%20Stone%20Tile%20Shower%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Light and Bright Aztec Stacked Stone Backsplash in Orlando, FL</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/light-and-bright-aztec-stacked-stone-backsplash-in-orlando-fl/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Light and Bright Aztec Stacked Stone Backsplash in Orlando, FL" /><published>2017-03-14T11:51:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-14T11:51:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/light-and-bright-aztec-stacked-stone-backsplash-in-orlando-fl</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/light-and-bright-aztec-stacked-stone-backsplash-in-orlando-fl/">&lt;p&gt;When Norstone first introduced its Aztec XL Series panel to the market we needed some great photography of an installation to put on our website and we had to look no further than the kitchen backsplash of one of our amazing sales people for just the right opportunity. Even though the project was a complete kitchen renovation, including the removal of walls, leveling out a sunken breakfast nook, and the complete tear out and reconfiguration of all cabinets and appliances, the backsplash was definitely not an afterthought. Having the unique experience and background of helping our clients day in and day out plan for their own kitchen renovations, she knew that the backsplash would tie all the other materials together and was an important piece of the design puzzle of this space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Aztec%20Stacked%20Stone%20Kitchen%20Backsplash%20-%20Orlando,%20FL.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Aztec Stacked Stone Kitchen Backsplash Orlando, FL&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of all the things we love about this project and the Aztec &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/backsplash-tile-designs-norstone-industy-series/&quot;&gt;stacked stone backsplash&lt;/a&gt;, what draws our eye the most is the color of the stone itself. Two words we consistently use to describe our Aztec color is light and bright, and I think that really shines through in this project. The cabinets, countertop, and flooring in this space are all very neutral, which allows the Aztec backsplash, sitting right below eye level for most people, to come up and shine for you with big bright oranges, pinks, and marbled white and grey colors. While we absolutely love the rustic earth tones of a color like our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-color-series-designing-ochre-blend/&quot;&gt;Ochre Blend&lt;/a&gt;, the more muted accent colors of that product would create less of a pop in this space than the Aztec has. Color accents are an important part of good design, and this stone backsplash checks that box for this kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Aztec%20Stacked%20Stone%20Kitchen%20Island%20-%20Orlando,%20FL-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Aztec Stacked Stone Kitchen Island Orlando, FL&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next thing our eye catches in this kitchen is the mix of textures. The polished Danby marble countertop, shaker style cabinets, long and linear plank flooring, and stainless steel appliances all embody elements of the smoothness of modern design. The stacked stone backsplash becomes the perfect counterpoint to that smoothness by embracing the split face texture of natural stone and providing visual interest for the project from both a color and dimensionality standpoint. Even the round bulbs of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-school-pairing-lighting-fixtures-with-stone-veneer-for-amazing-results/&quot;&gt;Edison style light fixture&lt;/a&gt; juxtapose the more block geometry of the stone adding to the design “pop” the textured backsplash creates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Aztec%20Stacked%20Stone%20Backsplash%20Close%20Up%20-%20Orlando,%20FL.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Aztec Stacked Stone Backsplash Close Up Orlando, FL&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last takeaway we got from this project was affirmation on just how easy a project like this is to tackle. Start to finish, including the clean up and an afternoon photo session, the installation of the rock panels took less than 6 hours for one rookie installer.  Whether its products like our stacked stone rock panels or basalt interlocking mosaic tiles, it’s never been easier for your average &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-diy-infographic/&quot;&gt;DIY homeowner&lt;/a&gt; to tackle a project like this and really make an impact on their space. If you’ve got a project in mind that you’re considering stacked stone veneer for but aren’t sure where to get started, reach out to one of our design experts and see where the process takes you. One thing we know for sure is that you’ll get great advice because if our sales people can design an amazing looking kitchen like this one on a small budget just imagine what they can do for you!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">When Norstone first introduced its Aztec XL Series panel to the market we needed some great photography of an installation to put on our website and we had to look no further than the kitchen backsplash of one of our amazing sales people for just the right opportunity. Even though the project was a complete kitchen renovation, including the removal of walls, leveling out a sunken breakfast nook, and the complete tear out and reconfiguration of all cabinets and appliances, the backsplash was definitely not an afterthought. Having the unique experience and background of helping our clients day in and day out plan for their own kitchen renovations, she knew that the backsplash would tie all the other materials together and was an important piece of the design puzzle of this space.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/assets/images/Aztec%20Stacked%20Stone%20Backsplash%20-%20Orlando,%20FL.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Aztec%20Stacked%20Stone%20Backsplash%20-%20Orlando,%20FL%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Aztec%20Stacked%20Stone%20Backsplash%20-%20Orlando,%20FL%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Design School – Pairing Lighting Fixtures with Stone Veneer for Amazing Results</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-school-pairing-lighting-fixtures-with-stone-veneer-for-amazing-results/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Design School – Pairing Lighting Fixtures with Stone Veneer for Amazing Results" /><published>2017-03-05T21:28:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-05T21:28:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-school-pairing-lighting-fixtures-with-stone-veneer-for-amazing-results</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-school-pairing-lighting-fixtures-with-stone-veneer-for-amazing-results/">&lt;p&gt;Here at Norstone we’re always been cognizant of lighting and how it impacts the look of our products on our customer’s walls. The first thing most people think of in terms of lighting is the color of the light the space will have. Is it natural sunlight from a window, or LED, Fluorescent, Halogen or Incandescent from a fixture? Each of these light sources is going to have a different shade, ranging from the yellow tinge of an incandescent to the ultra pure white of some LEDs, and can make a significant impact on how stone veneer looks once installed. What we want to talk about today is not just the color of the light shining down on that stone, but the fixture itself. A simple web search will net you pages and pages of different light fixtures in every shape, size, color, and material, so with endless options, let’s cut through some of that clutter and share with you some of our favorite pairings of lighting fixtures and stone veneer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Ochre%20Blend%20Feature%20Wall%20-%20Atlanta%20Loft.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ochre Blend Feature Wall in Atlanta Loft Space&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This first project shows off a stunning &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-color-series-designing-ochre-blend/&quot;&gt;Ochre Blend&lt;/a&gt; Feature Wall in a downtown Atlanta loft space. The prominent circular drop chandelier is perfectly colored to blend in with the base brown and grey tones of the Ochre color, and is also sized correctly for the space. The simple styling of this fixture also works well with the loft styling including the concrete floors and ceiling. Taking a closer look at the space you’ll also see a small row of Halogen pendants set to illuminate the stacked stone wall, which will create a dramatic effect at night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Ivory%20Rock%20Panel%20Wine%20Room%20Wall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ivory Stone Veneer Wine Cellar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Light fixtures don’t always have to be seen to have an impact, which is what we have in this next project featuring our Ivory Rock Panels set behind a wine rack system, lit up from both the bottom and top with LED strip lighting. The clean white color of the LED light adds to the modern feel of the metal wine racks and sleek vibe of the room. Ivory is one of our favorite colors to work with from a lighting standpoint as the type of lighting used can really impact how it ends up looking. Under incandescent lighting this same wall would have a much yellower hue and the stone would look more rustic and less contemporary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Ochre%20Stacked%20Stone%20Wall%20-%20Sunburst%20Chandelier%20Austin,%20TX-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ochre Stacked Stone Feature Wall with Sunburst Chandelier in Austin, TX&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This next one is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/ochre-ochre-everywhere-in-this-magnificent-austin-tx-modern-home/&quot;&gt;Residential Project in Austin, TX&lt;/a&gt;  that has one of our favorite lighting features serving as a focal point chandelier for an informal dining space. The stacked stone feature wall done behind the table has loads and loads of texture and a carefully design block geometry to give it an appealing modern yet rustic look. The fixture captures those same qualities with its use of one shape in a layered format. The warm glow of an incandescent bulb adds to the sunburst look of this very cool and modern light fixture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Basalt%20Ash%20Grey%203D%20Stone%20Panel%20-%20Modern%20Fan%20-%20Tampa,%20FL.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Basalt Grey 3D Panel on Modern Fireplacein Tampa, FL&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not all light fixtures are just lights as this next project in Tampa, FL shows us. Our Basalt 3D Stone Panel in Ash Grey is featured on this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-trends-when-it-comes-to-stone-smooth-is-in/&quot;&gt;smooth stone fireplace&lt;/a&gt; project. Featuring a long and skinny format gas fireplace, adorned with an ultra modern stainless steel and glass border and screen, this fireplace also has a large inset TV to complete the contemporary vibe. The lighting fixture consisting of a simple domed globe and a modern styled high volume fan works well with the smooth stone wall. The simplicity of the dome ties in nicely with the smoothness of the stone and the sharp angles of the fan blade suggest that it will move a lot of air around, linking up nicely with the industrial chic nature of this polished grey stone wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/White%20Quartz%20Stone%20Veneer%20Wall%20-%20Cafe%20Sign%20-%20Orlando,%20FL.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;White Quartz Stone Veneer Cafe Wall in Orlando, FL&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our last project reminds us that a light fixture doesn’t always have to be on the ceiling. Set against the crisp look of our White Quartz Rock Panels, this shadowbox cafe signs with Edison style incandescent bulbs contrasts nicely with the wall behind it. Equally beautiful when illuminated or turned off, this unique fixture is both stylish in design and function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some things to avoid when pairing lighting and stone veneer are fixtures that overpower or clash with stone on size, shape, or color. Misdirected or lack of lighting can also detract from the overall design – stone walls are so beautiful and such a natural focal point that the last thing you want is lighting that misses its mark or leaves you in the dark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While lighting is normally one of the last things to be installed during a construction project, don’t wait to start planning for it until after everything else is done. It might take a while to find that perfect fixture, and it’s a lot easier to plan for and place fixture locations before and during construction than after. So the next time you find yourself planning a stone veneer project remember all the amazing ways lighting can enhance your design.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Here at Norstone we’re always been cognizant of lighting and how it impacts the look of our products on our customer’s walls. The first thing most people think of in terms of lighting is the color of the light the space will have. Is it natural sunlight from a window, or LED, Fluorescent, Halogen or Incandescent from a fixture? Each of these light sources is going to have a different shade, ranging from the yellow tinge of an incandescent to the ultra pure white of some LEDs, and can make a significant impact on how stone veneer looks once installed. What we want to talk about today is not just the color of the light shining down on that stone, but the fixture itself. A simple web search will net you pages and pages of different light fixtures in every shape, size, color, and material, so with endless options, let’s cut through some of that clutter and share with you some of our favorite pairings of lighting fixtures and stone veneer.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/assets/images/Ochre%20Stacked%20Stone%20Wall%20-%20Sunburst%20Chandelier%20Austin,%20TX.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Design%20School%20-%20How%20to%20Pick%20a%20Great%20Lighting%20Fixture%20for%20your%20stone%20veneer%20wall%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Design%20School%20-%20How%20to%20Pick%20a%20Great%20Lighting%20Fixture%20for%20your%20stone%20veneer%20wall%22%7D" /></entry></feed>