<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-08-18T11:04:37-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/</id><title type="html">Norstone USA</title><subtitle>New dimensions in natural stone.</subtitle><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><entry><title type="html">280 Park Ave Rooftop Pool Stone Feature Wall</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/nyc-rooftop-pool-stone-feature-wall/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="280 Park Ave Rooftop Pool Stone Feature Wall" /><published>2017-08-14T11:17:10-04:00</published><updated>2017-08-14T11:17:10-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/280-park-ave-rooftop-pool-stone-feature-wall</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/nyc-rooftop-pool-stone-feature-wall/">&lt;p&gt;We haven’t featured an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/rock-panels/ivory/&quot;&gt;Ivory Rock Panel&lt;/a&gt; project in a while, so I took a look at our project photo collection and came across this great rooftop pool project in New York City.  It’s actually several years old, but I had a great time looking back and appreciating some of the unique details of this project, like the closely spaced outside and inside off angle miter cut corner.  Some of our Norstone team lives in the Big Apple, and a bunch of us enjoying swimming for exercise and fun, so this great project is right up our alley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/08/14/Indoor%20Pool%20Ledgestone%20Feature%20Wall%20-%20New%20York%20City.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Indoor Pool Ivory Ledgestone Feature Wall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bulk of the stone is installed on a large feature wall abutting the short end of the pool.  The Ivory color matches up nicely with the light neutral tones of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/travertine-tiles-norstone-designer-series/&quot;&gt;travertine pool coping&lt;/a&gt;, which create a nice contrast with the aqua blue of the pool.  One of the nice features of a stacked stone wall like this is the noise deflection properties of the stone.  Anyone that’s ever spent some time in an indoor pool knows how loud it can be with sound slapping off all the flat surfaces like the deck, windows, ceiling, and even the water which transmits sound exceptionally well.  A highly textured product like ledge stone bounces sound waves off in many different directions, helping to diffuse the sound.  The same reason why our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/project/rockport/&quot;&gt;stacked stone works well in concert halls&lt;/a&gt; is the same reason why it makes this room just a little quieter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/08/14/Indoor%20Pool%20Ledgestone%20Feature%20Wall%20-%20New%20York%20City%20Skyline%20Views-1.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Indoor Pool Ledgestone Feature Wall on New York Rooftop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For an indoor rooftop pool, the architect did an excellent job incorporating natural light and taking advantage of the amazing views you get in this prime Manhattan location.  From a design standpoint, the challenge on indoor pools is often how to de-sterilize the feel of the space where the hard surfaces of the deck and pool itself tend to dominate.  The stacked stone feature wall is a great option as it’ll be incredibly durable and easier to maintain than a plain wall or window, but at the same time the ledge stone look brings in a surface with an outdoor/  natural feel to it.  Indoor pools also often suffer from lack of natural light, many even are below ground with no natural light at all, making this surely a selling point for the residents of the building.  The peaked glass ceiling above the pool keeps the sun in and weather out.  And lastly, let’s not forget about the views of the Flatiron district and surrounding areas which give this space a distinctly New York feel, something you can’t say about every pool on the island.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/08/14/Indoor%20Pool%20Ledgestone%20Feature%20Wall%20Inside%20Outside%20Miter%20Corner%20-%20New%20York%20City.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Indoor Pool knee wall with off angle mitered corners&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a stone company, the part of this installation that really catches our eye is the amazing job the installer has done through a section of half wall where the stone traverses an inside then outside corner in a small area, all at an off angle needing a miter cut.  This knee wall, separating the pool from the stairway does a great job tying together and establishing a design them with the main stacked stone accent wall on the far side of the pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/08/14/Indoor%20Pool%20Ledgestone%20Feature%20Wall%20Outside%20Finger%20Joint%20Corner%20-%20New%20York%20City.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Indoor Pool knee wall using Norstone Finger Joint Corner Units&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This next photo taken from a slightly different angle shows the difference between our finger jointed corner units, used to turn the outside 90 degree corner from the stairway and the previously mentioned off angle miter cut corners.  Kudos to the installation team for a job well done with the mitered corners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While not every pool has amazing views of the New York City skyline, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/summer-s-here-jump-into-these-amazing-pools-designed-with-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;pools are a great project to use stacked stone&lt;/a&gt; on.  From the water line tile, to a raised beam water feature, to a knee wall flowing into an outdoor kitchen or lanai, stacked stone is a durable product that will stand up to the test of the harsh pool environment while also creating or adding to the natural feel that most pool design seeks to create.  So whatever your latitude, or whether your pool is inside or outside, be sure to consider a natural stone product for your next pool project.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Swimming and New York City are two things close to the hearts of the team at Norstone, which makes this cool enclosed rooftop pool that used our Ivory Rock Panels on some feature walls a place we'd enjoy getting our laps in before or after the work day.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2017/08/14/Indoor%20Pool%20Ledgestone%20Feature%20Wall%20-%20New%20York%20City%20Skyline%20Views.JPG%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Ledgestone%20Feature%20Wall%20on%20Indoor%20Pool%20with%20New%20York%20City%20Skyline%20Views%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Ivory%20Ledgestone%20Feature%20Wall%20on%20Indoor%20Pool%20with%20New%20York%20City%20Skyline%20Views%20and%20a%20glass%20roof%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Design, Spec, Build – Know the Players of Your Next Construction Project</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-spec-build/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Design, Spec, Build – Know the Players of Your Next Construction Project" /><published>2017-08-06T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-08-06T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-spec-build-know-the-players-of-your-next-construction-project-big-or-small</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-spec-build/">&lt;p&gt;Depending on the size of your &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/&quot;&gt;stone veneer&lt;/a&gt; project, a bunch of different people with lots of different skill sets could be involved.  One of the things that can make projects confusing, even for those of us with experience, is that sometimes those skill sets overlap and what role someone may fill on one project can be different on the next project.  To really understand who the players are in a construction project, big or small, let’s take a look at three of the major steps in the process of taking an idea and building it into reality - Design, Specify, Build.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;design&quot;&gt;Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The design phase of a construction project is pretty clear cut.  The needs and desires of the client are determined and balanced against things like project location, budget, and construction practices.  An architect is often relied on for their expertise in this phase.  For projects both big and small architects perform the crucial role of drafting the detailed blueprints and construction documents necessary for the “build team” to actually take a project through permitting and construct the job with.  These experts take into account things like the added weight a ledge stone accent wall will add and what that means to the structure of a building or construction method of a wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/08/07/Design%20Specify%20Build%20-%20Architect%20Meeting%20with%20Client.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Architect meeting with client during the design phase of a construction project&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lines blur considerably in the design phase when you start talking about projects that are more renovation in nature, and generally speaking don’t require a building permit, for example &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/light-and-bright-aztec-stacked-stone-backsplash-in-orlando-fl/&quot;&gt;upgrading the tile on a kitchen backsplash&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/two-toned-modern-fireplace-in-ft-collins-co/&quot;&gt;adding stone veneer to a fireplace&lt;/a&gt;.  A competent contractor, or sometimes even the homeowner, can fill the gap and perform the design and crucial planning steps for projects in this realm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;specify&quot;&gt;Specify&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The specification phase of a project is always exciting because it involves picking out a lot of the materials to be used and detailing out how specific things are to be built on the project.  While its not quite the same level of satisfaction as seeing concrete get poured or walls get painted, it does often provide a great visual introduction to what the completed project will look like it.  Larger projects will have multiple teams of designers working on specific areas, such as interiors and landscaping, and sometimes the architect even plays a dual role as specifier as well.  Owners and / or owners reps meet frequently with the design team and are heavily involved making material selections during this phase and making sure the project is moving forward and on budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/08/07/Design%20Specify%20Build%20-%20Design%20Center.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Design center used in the specification and selection phase of a construction project&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For smaller projects, homeowners often find themselves in the role of specifier.  They might be re-doing their fireplace in a stone veneer and had the “design” discussion with a quality contractor, but now its up to them to research and find a product that they love and that works for the project.  Depending on the scope of any given project and that homeowner’s desire or ability to make those decisions, many of our clients often enlist the help of a designer, sometimes on an hourly engagement basis, other times handing over complete control of the project, to help with this phase of the project.  It can be intimidating for a homeowner to try and learn everything there is to know about a product like stone veneer or ledge stone, so leveraging an expert is a great way to save time and often times money as well by avoiding costly mistakes in material selection and ordering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;build&quot;&gt;Build&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with many things in life, successful prep work without taking any short cuts in the Design or Specify phases is the key to a successful Build.  On large projects, clients will be working with a general contractor whose job it is to manage multiple sub contractors performing a variety of work and ensure the construction is being done according to the plans, according to building codes, and to the  expected level of quality their clients demand.  On smaller projects a homeowner can sometimes act as their own general contractor, perhaps working with an electrician to wire some under cabinet lighting on a backsplash project and a tile installer to actually lay and grout the tile.  However the project is being managed, making sure &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/selecting-the-right-installer-for-your-next-tile-or-stone-project/&quot;&gt;a great contractor is selected&lt;/a&gt; for the work is always important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/08/07/Design%20Specify%20Build%20-%20Stone%20Veneer%20Installation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stone masons installing stone veneer panels during the build phase of a construction project&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter the size of the project or how formal or informal each phase is, all successful projects are designed, specified, and built.  Even for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-diy-infographic/&quot;&gt;DIY project&lt;/a&gt; where the homeowner is handling all three phases, laying out the project in this manner will help lead to a successful project, and cut out extra trips to the hardware store or costly re-orders or returns of products that weren’t planned for correctly.  The team at Norstone is well versed in working through this process on any size project so contact us today to start planning your next natural stone veneer project.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">At Norstone we get to work with clients on all levels of projects – from a small backsplash or fireplace where our homeowner client is installing the stone veneer themselves to large architecturally specified projects that can take years to develop. If you've ever found yourself in the middle of a big project and aren't quite sure who is responsible for what, here's a great guide we compiled to make things clearer for us and our clients.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2017/08/07/Design%20Specify%20Build%20Icon%20Collage.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Design%20Specify%20Build%20Icon%20Collage%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Collage%20of%20icons%20representing%20the%20design,%20specification,%20and%20build%20processes%20of%20construction%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Banking on the Great Design of Ebony Basalt 3D Panels</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/basalt-3d-bank/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Banking on the Great Design of Ebony Basalt 3D Panels" /><published>2017-08-02T17:58:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-08-02T17:58:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/banking-on-the-great-design-of-ebony-basalt-3d-panels</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/basalt-3d-bank/">&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/&quot;&gt;stone veneer products&lt;/a&gt; have been used on a lot of banks and other financial institutions across the country.  There’s no doubt that a seeing a strong and durable product like stone is an ideal parallel for how banks want to be perceived by the public, especially as it relates to being a safe place to store and save your hard earned money.  While a lot of the banks we’ve worked with have opted for the ledge stone look of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/stacked-stone-cladding/&quot;&gt;Standard Series Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/thin-stone-veneer-panels/&quot;&gt;XL Series Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt;, we really love the cutting edge choices made by the design team of this credit union located in central Washington state.  Not only was the selection of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/basalt-stone-panels/black-stone/&quot;&gt;Ebony Basalt 3D Stone Panel&lt;/a&gt; a bold and modern move, the way it was implemented across various features both on the interior and exterior of this project deserves a  closer look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/08/02/Basalt%203D%20Ebony%20-%20Commercial%20-%20Credit%20Union%2010.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Basalt Ebony Stone Veneer on Exterior of Bank as seen from the road&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The building as seen from the street looks unlike a traditional bank, with the design of the building jutting off at various sharp angles and an eclectic mix of neutral colors.  Prominent in this elevation is the stone accent wall made of Basalt 3D Panels, which is set slightly in front of the main wall and extends slightly higher than the first floor of the building, creating a nice architectural touch.  The dark color of the stone veneer matches up with the metal trim work used on the rest of the building and serves as a focal point and accenting color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/08/02/Basalt%203D%20Ebony%20-%20Commercial%20-%20Credit%20Union%2011-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Basalt Ebony Stone Veneer used as the background on a bank's signage&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up close this stone veneer blade wall is even more interesting to look at.  The design team chose to install the 3D Stone Panels in a vertical orientation, meaning the long dimension of each unit is set along the vertical axis, or 90 degrees off from the more traditional horizontal orientation.  The end result is that vertical orientation accentuates the height of the feature wall.  The clean geometry of the product also shines through in this photo, with the stone veneer panels creating loads of texture with a modern, very clean lined look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/08/02/Basalt%203D%20Ebony%20-%20Commercial%20-%20Credit%20Union%208.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Basalt Ebony Stone Veneer used on the exterior of a bank near the entrance&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The parking lot approach to the building reveals another distinct stone veneer blade wall, this time juxtaposing a circular entrance way, extending all the way up to become the highest point of the entire building.  We love the off angle nature of this whole building and seeing that continue on the rising slope of this feature wall.  The cut out in the stone accent wall on the second floor right above the entryway is a subtle feature that adds interest and great visuals to the overall design of this exterior installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/08/02/Basalt%203D%20Ebony%20-%20Commercial%20-%20Credit%20Union%203.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Basalt Ebony Stone Veneer column bases&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A line of architectural pergolas line the paver walkway from the parking lot to the entrance of the bank and the design team thoughtfully chose to clad the bottom of the support columns in the same stone veneer used on the exterior accent walls.  The material not only provides a nice tie in between this space and the main building, but also offers a durable building material option for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stone-veneer-columns-norstone-classroom-series/&quot;&gt;bases of these stone column&lt;/a&gt; supports, without sacrificing anything in the way of look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/08/02/Basalt%203D%20Ebony%20-%20Commercial%20-%20Credit%20Union%206.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Basalt Ebony Stone Veneer Lobby and Reception Desk Accent Walls&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the outside of this bank didn’t convince you to move your money there, the inside continues to impress with a continuation of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/ledgestone-norstone-industry-series/&quot;&gt;exterior ledge stone feature wall&lt;/a&gt; into the lobby area, with the stone going vertical from the floor to the vaulted two story ceiling.  A super cool design on the wall behind the reception desk has the stone veneer fanning out from the ceiling down to the floor and is a great background for the commercial signage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for taking a look at this cool project with us and we hope it &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/outside-the-box-stone-design-ideas-for-your-next-remodel-or-new-build/&quot;&gt;inspires your next stone veneer project&lt;/a&gt;, big or small. Contact one of our design specialists so we can show you how our varied and unique line of stone veneer products can transform your space today!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">This credit union in central Washington state raises the bar from a design standpoint as far as financial institutions are concerned. Let's take a look at how our Ebony Basalt 3D Panels were used extensively on the interior and exterior of this project and how this credit union gives you a lot to look at when you stop by.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2017/08/02/Basalt%203D%20Ebony%20-%20Commercial%20-%20Credit%20Union%2011.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Ebony%20Basalt%203D%20Stone%20Veneer%20Signage%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Signage%20at%20a%20bank%20in%20Washington%20state%20that%20used%20Norstone%203D%20Basalt%20panels%20in%20Ebony%20on%20a%20vertical%20orientation.%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How To Install Stacked Stone On Curved Walls</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-install-stacked-stone-on-curved-walls/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How To Install Stacked Stone On Curved Walls" /><published>2017-07-23T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-23T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-install-stacked-stone-on-curved-walls</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-install-stacked-stone-on-curved-walls/">&lt;p&gt;One of big things that makes our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/stacked-stone-cladding/&quot;&gt;stacked stone rock panel products&lt;/a&gt; so easy to work with is that its already been pre-assembled into a highly calibrated ready to install unit, that is more comparable to tile than to traditional loose hand stacked stone.  The panel system provides a lot of benefits, chief among them the ability for less skilled labor, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-diy-infographic/&quot;&gt;DIY installation of stacked stone&lt;/a&gt; by homeowners.  One of the drawbacks of the panel system is the lack of flexibility of the panel, in particular when working on curved or radius walls.  However, there are lots of great ways products like ours can be used on curved walls, so let’s take a look at our guidelines for using stacked stone on radius walls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-1-know-the-radius-of-your-wall&quot;&gt;Step 1: Know the Radius of Your Wall&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step in understanding if a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/&quot;&gt;stacked stone panel product&lt;/a&gt; will work on a curved wall is to know what the actual curve,or radius of the wall is.  Radius is actually a unit of measure, normally given in feet, and expresses the length from the middle of a circle to the edge.  In other words, if you took a curved wall, and extended that curve out using an imaginary line to complete a full circle, the radius measurement would be how far it is from the center of the circle to any point on your wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/07/24/Stacked%20Stone%20Radius%20Wall%20University%20Lounge.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Stacked Stone Curved Wall University Lounge&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re working with a set of construction documents or blueprints, the radius is often called out, or can be calculated via many CAD programs.  If you’re retrofitting an existing wall with stacked stone you can tie a string between the two ends of the curved wall, measure the length of the string and the farthest point between the string and the wall, and using your high school trigonometry, or more likely one of many easy to use online calculators, calculate the radius.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our rule of thumb is that any wall with a radius of 20 feet or greater can use our rock panel products without modifying the product.  For walls with radius measurements less than 20 feet, multiple options are explored below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-2-understand-installation-techniques&quot;&gt;Step 2: Understand Installation Techniques&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For walls with radius measurements less than 20 feet the primary methods for making stacked stone panels “fit” is to either cut down the panel into smaller sections and / or cut the edges of each panel for a tighter fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/07/24/Stacked%20Stone%20Radius%20Garden%20Wall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stacked Stone Curved Garden Wall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Norstone Rock Panels have a standard orientation of 6” tall x 24” wide, so the first step when working on a radius wall less than 20 feet would involve cutting the panels in half (6”x12”).  This introduces twice as many vertical seams into the job which allows the tile to be more flexible along a curved wall since most of the curve is accommodated where two panels come together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to cutting the the panels down in size, the vertical edges can be cut with a miter saw to come together more tightly along a tightly curved wall.  This takes the right tools, and some skill and patience, but when done correctly on tight radius work like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/summer-s-here-jump-into-these-amazing-pools-designed-with-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;stacked stone pool and spa surrounds&lt;/a&gt;, the results are amazing.  The garden wall in the photo above was installed personally the CEO of a major tile distribution company in Florida who has a lifetime of tile setting experience, and who personally attested to the ease of installation of Norstone stone panels in radius applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-3-understand-convex-vs-concave&quot;&gt;Step 3: Understand Convex vs Concave&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An important part of installing stacked stone on a curved wall is knowing if the stone is going on the convex or the concave side of the curved wall.  Convex means the surface curves outward while concave means the surface curves inward.  When working on a concave wall, the front of the stacked stone panels are going to be the tightest and potentially need some careful trimming for a precise tight fit.  Convex is just the opposite in that the back of the panels might need trimming for a clean fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/07/24/Stacked%20Stone%20Concave%20and%20Convex%20Radius%20Wall%20Outdoor%20Hot%20Tub.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Stacked Stone Concave and Convex Curved Wall Outdoor Hot Tub&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-4-consider-alternatives&quot;&gt;Step 4: Consider Alternatives&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a wall with a tight radius, but absolutely love the look of stacked stone in the space, the one alternative we see many clients go with is flipping the orientation of the panel to 6” wide and 24” tall.  While this definitely changes the look of product, accentuating the long linear feel vertically instead of horizontally, the 6” width of the panel allows for a far more flexible installation.  Don’t be afraid to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/outside-the-box-stone-design-ideas-for-your-next-remodel-or-new-build/&quot;&gt;think outside the box with your next stacked stone installation&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/07/24/Vertical%20Stacked%20Stone%20Radius%20Wall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Vertical Stacked Stone Curved Wall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Radius walls are in many ways a great design contrast to the traditional flat walls that stacked stone is commonly associated with, and could be a great feature in your next interior or exterior project.  If you have specific questions about how stacked stone will install on your radius wall or even just need a little help getting started, contact us today and one of our team members, highly skilled in both design and technical expertise, can help out.  Until then, keep an eye out for curved walls in your day to day and just think how much better they’d look covered in stacked stone!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Curved or radius walls provide a unique opportunity to use stacked stone in a way not traditionally seen. We've gotten a chance to work on some great radius projects and wanted to share our tips and guidelines for using stacked stone on radius walls.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2017/07/24/Stacked%20Stone%20Radius%20Wall%20Medical%20Office%20Lobby-1.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Stacked%20Stone%20Curved%20Wall%20Medical%20Office%20Lobby%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Curved%20wall%20starting%20behind%20a%20reception%20desk%20and%20continuing%20over%20a%20large%20glass%20doorway%20in%20a%20modern%20industrial%20styled%20medical%20office.%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Basalt 3D Ledge Stone in America’s Heartland</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/3d-ledge-stone-kansas/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Basalt 3D Ledge Stone in America's Heartland" /><published>2017-07-17T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-17T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/basalt-3d-ledge-stone-in-america-s-heartland</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/3d-ledge-stone-kansas/">&lt;p&gt;The middle of the country often gets a bad rap in terms of being progressive in terms of home design.  We’ve been fortunate enough to work and place our stone on many projects in all parts of the country, and know there are great designers and projects happening everywhere!  None more so than this new construction home in Lawrence, KS that one of our custom home builder clients recently completed.  Featuring our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/basalt-stone-panels/ash-grey-stone/&quot;&gt;Grey Basalt 3D Ledge Stone&lt;/a&gt; product in multiple applications throughout, this home embraces a subdued modern design without being over the top.  What truly sets this home apart is the detail in every part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/selecting-the-right-installer-for-your-next-tile-or-stone-project/&quot;&gt;stone installation&lt;/a&gt; which all add up in making this space award worthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/07/18/Grey%20Basalt%20Ledge%20Stone%20Outdoor%20Fireplace%20Kansas.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Outdoor fireplace and tv recessed into column clad in basalt 3d ledge stone&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting on the rear patio, the Grey Basalt 3D &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/ledgestone-norstone-industry-series/&quot;&gt;ledge stone&lt;/a&gt; is used on a large support column which also holds a stainless steel gas fireplace and an outdoor television.  With many of the accouterments of an interior living room, this patio really captures the essence of an outdoor “living” space.  From a stone standpoint, the installation team skillfully and beautifully navigated outside and inside corners, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-install-a-flat-screen-tv-on-a-stacked-stone-wall/&quot;&gt;flat screen tv recess&lt;/a&gt;, and even installed the stone on the overhanging portion of this column.  All of these elements work together nicely complementing the wooded vista of the backyard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/07/18/Grey%20Basalt%20Ledge%20Stone%20Patio%20Kansas.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rear elevation view of modern styled home outside of Kansas with grey basalt 3d ledge stone accents&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The backside of the aforementioned column as viewed from the yard might look like just a stone wall, but again, the details of this project shine through upon closer inspection.  We love the use of non 90 degree angles on this column – even though we love the way our outside corner units work, we can appreciate the use of an off angle and how it creates a juxtaposition to the clean lines of the rest of the house.  The angles of the column play nicely with the curves of the spiral staircase, and not to be missed is the large boulders dividing the grass from the building.  The natural stone aspect of these boulders helps bridge the gap between the wooded property and stone accented home.  There are some practical considerations when installing stacked stone in a freeze / thaw climate like Kansas which this builder addressed through the use of a waterproofing and anti fracture membrane applied between the substrate and setting materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/07/18/Grey%20Basalt%20Ledge%20Stone%20Bar%20Kansas.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Modern styled bar with grey 3D ledge stone used on facing and backsplash&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interior spaces of this home pick up right where the exterior leaves off, including this amazing bar which used the Grey 3D Basalt ledge stone panels on the facing and backsplash.  The minimalist hardware used on the shelving fits right into the modern look of this space, but probably the most impressive detail is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-school-pairing-lighting-fixtures-with-stone-veneer-for-amazing-results/&quot;&gt;interaction of the stone and the lighting&lt;/a&gt;.  The ceiling cans and LED strips used behind the shelving hardware looks fantastic, but what really catches our eye is the undermount fixtures shining from the bar top onto the face.  Coming at us from below eye level, with ideal lighting, you really notice the super clean geometric lines of this stone veneer as well as the volume of texture created by the variations in stone depth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/07/18/Grey%20Basalt%20Ledge%20Stone%20Fireplace%20Kansas.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;TV and fireplace feature wall &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of detail, no space in this project shines brighter than living room feature wall.  The installation team deserves a standing ovation for their skilled maneuvering of the the stone into the recesses of the gas fireplace and tv, as well as working around the floating shelves flanking each side of the bump out.  The under mount lighting shows off the same great texture that we admired on the bar face and the stone continuing even behind the television shows top level attention to detail that all comes together to make this space look amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you’ve enjoyed touring the various stone installations on this home as much as we have.  Remember, good design knows no boundaries,so no matter where you are, or what your project is, dream it up, call us up, and let’s get started turning your dream project into reality!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">We were blown away when we saw photos of this client's project recently completed about an hours drive outside of Kansas City, KS. The detail the designers and installers wove into the installation is pretty extraordinary. Come take a look inside with us and see what makes this project so special.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2017/07/18/Grey%20Basalt%20Ledge%20Stone%20Fireplace%20Kansas-1.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Grey%20Basalt%203D%20Ledge%20Stone%20Fireplace%20and%20TV%20Feature%20Wall%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Gas%20fireplace%20and%20big%20screen%20tv%20recessed%20into%20a%20stone%20wall%20clad%20in%20grey%20basalt%203D%20ledge%20stone%20flanked%20on%20either%20side%20by%20floating%20shelves%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Pick the Perfect Flooring to Complement a Stacked Stone Wall</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/flooring-for-stacked-stone/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Pick the Perfect Flooring to Complement a Stacked Stone Wall" /><published>2017-07-11T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-11T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-pair-flooring-with-stacked-stone</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/flooring-for-stacked-stone/">&lt;p&gt;Flooring is a detail not be overlooked when working on a stacked stone wall project.  The right flooring  can complement the wall from a color standpoint, either as matching or contrasting in shade, as well as in pattern and texture.  Let’s take a look at some of our favorite &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/project/&quot;&gt;stone veneer projects&lt;/a&gt; and how the right flooring was used to enhance the overall look of the space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/07/12/White%20Stacked%20Stone%20Modern%20Fireplace.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;White Stacked Stone Modern Fireplace with ventless insert&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This first project is a study in the classic contrast of black on white, two colors that pair well together in both a formal and modern way.  This particular space shows off the great texture and consistent color of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/rock-panels/white/&quot;&gt;White Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt;, which is contrasted beautifully with the stagger set large format black tiles.  A detail that is easily overlooked is the short “tile kick” that is used as a trim piece on the bottom couple inches of the wall, which helps transition the texture of the wall down to the smoothness of the floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/07/12/White%20Stone%20Veneer%20Hotel%20Lobby%20Fireplace%20Alberta.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;White Stacked Stone Modern Fireplace in Hotel Lobby Alberta Canada&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This next project also features another stunning White Rock Panel fireplace with dark flooring, but what we love the most about this space is the random patterned carpet that creates a wonderful contrast with the starkness of the multi story white fireplace.  A carpet with this type of design just won’t work with a patterned wall, resulting in a very “busy look”, but is the perfect complement to the modern glass and white stone backdrop of this hotel lobby in Alberta, Canada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/07/12/Basalt%203D%20Ash%20Grey%20Corner%20Fireplace%20Washington.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Basalt Grey Stone Veneer Panel on Corner Fireplace in bank lobby&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carpet sometimes gets a bad rap from homeowners because it can lack the overall durability of a hard surface like wood, stone, or tile, but the design community certainly embraces carpet for its ability to create a complex pattern or look that can’t be replicated on a hard surface.  This next project is a great example of that idea, with the carpet capturing the overall “beige” color pallete of the space while featuring a complex cross hatch pattern that meshes nicely with the clean line geometry and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-trends-when-it-comes-to-stone-smooth-is-in/&quot;&gt;smooth face of the Grey Basalt 3D Panels&lt;/a&gt; on this unique corner fireplace in the upper lobby of a bank in Washington state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/07/12/Ochre%20Stacked%20Stone%20Office%20Wall%20Denver.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ochre Stacked Stone Dividing Wall in Architecture Firm office Denver&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;White and grey stone is easy to contrast, but the multi color blend of our Ochre Rock Panels can pose more a design challenge in terms of selecting the right flooring color.  This architect’s office in Denver, CO selected a deep brown carpet which really pulls out the “earth” tones of the Ochre color and is a nice backdrop for the lighter rust and rose colored accents that are part of the blend.  The unique carpet border around this partial wall which separates two spaces in the firm’s lobby also helps to create that division through the use of contrasting color with the lighter carpet abutting it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/07/12/Basalt%203D%20Ash%20Grey%20Bathroom%20Feature%20Wall%20Dallas-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Luxury Modern Master bathroom with marble floors and honed grey stone veneer wall in Dallas&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More subtle contrast can be found in this next project, both in terms of color and material selection.  The darkest parts of the polished white / grey marble floor are basically the same color as the Grey Basalt 3D accent wall in this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-bathrooms-designing-norstone-series/&quot;&gt;exquisite natural stone master bath&lt;/a&gt; in Dallas, TX.  The use of natural material in this space, from the marble on the floors, basalt on the walls, and even the unique floating wood tub surround all complement each other without the need to contrast against a man-made or synthetic material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/07/12/Basalt%20Interlocking%20Ash%20Grey%20San%20Francisco%20Patio.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;City Backyard in San Francisco featuring artificial turf and a grey interlocking tile feature wall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our last featured space reminds us to think &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/outside-the-box-stone-design-ideas-for-your-next-remodel-or-new-build/&quot;&gt;outside the box when it comes to your flooring options&lt;/a&gt;.  It would have been so easy to use any sort of grey cement or stone paver or similar hardscape product in this unique San Francisco “city backyard”, but the use of artificial turf makes this space far more inviting and memorable.  The lush green color considerably brightens up the area and gives it an outside feel, and the plush texture is a nice foil to the smooth honed finish of the Grey Basalt Interlocking Mosaic Tile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for taking a look at some of our favorite projects and how flooring can really add to the overall look of a space where stacked stone veneer has been used.  We’d love to see photos of the flooring our readers used with their projects, or if you’re considering what kind of flooring to use on your next stacked stone project, let our design team guide your way and reach out to us today.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">You've designed and maybe already installed an amazing stone wall, now use these tips to make sure the flooring in the space is just as on point as the wall you can't keep your eyes off of.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2017/07/12/Basalt%203D%20Ash%20Grey%20Bathroom%20Feature%20Wall%20Dallas.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Flooring%20to%20Match%20a%20Stone%20Veneer%20Wall%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Modern%20luxury%20bathroom%20featuring%20complimentary%20light%20grey%20polished%20marble%20flooring%20and%20grey%20honed%20stone%20veneer%20wall.%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Modern Stacked Stone Masterpiece in Asheville, NC</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/modern-stacked-stone-masterpiece-in-asheville-nc/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Modern Stacked Stone Masterpiece in Asheville, NC" /><published>2017-07-06T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-06T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/modern-stacked-stone-masterpiece-in-asheville-nc</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/modern-stacked-stone-masterpiece-in-asheville-nc/">&lt;p&gt;Having never visited Asheville, NC, the team at Norstone had a preconceived notion that most of the high end architecture in the area was “Southern Grand” in line with the famous Gilded era Biltmore Estate, one of the areas biggest tourist destinations.  There’s no doubt that Southern Revival Architecture has a place in this pocket of the North Carolina’s Blueridge mountains, but what really took us by surprise was this Modern Masterpiece of a home that a designer client of ours completed recently that would fit right in if its was located in Miami Beach or the Hollywood Hills and most importantly the clients were thrilled with the results.  Let’s take a look at how the our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/thin-stone-veneer-panels/charcoal/&quot;&gt;Charcoal XL Stacked Stone Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt; were used to set this project apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/07/07/Modern%20Stacked%20Stone%20Patio%20Asheville.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Modern Stacked Stone Patio in Asheville, NC&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The modern design of this home is most evident in the low pitched roof lines and overall clean lines of the space.  Extensive use of brushed stainless on the soffitt and trim work contrast nicely with the color and texture of the Charcoal XL stone veneer used on twin accent walls coming out from the interior of the home and terminating on the rear patio.  A massive fold up glass partition wall allows for the interior and exterior spaces to come together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/07/07/Modern%20Stacked%20Stone%20Flagstone%20Patio%20Asheville.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Modern Stacked Stone Flagstone Patio in Asheville, NC&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An extended &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-patios-designing-norstone-series/&quot;&gt;natural stone patio&lt;/a&gt; of various size and patterned square and rectangle pavers is a unique and interesting design choice.  The size and shape are clearly meant to tie back to the clean lines and sharp corners of the home, yet the irregular spacing and mixed in landscaping allow a nice transition from the modern feel of the home to the beautiful nature and lake views this property calls home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/07/07/Modern%20Stacked%20Stone%20Fireplace%20Asheville.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Modern Stacked Stone Fireplace in Asheville, NC&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The view, not only of the amazing corner stone fireplace and large stacked stone accent wall, but also of the lakefront takes center stage when inside the home.  The fireplace is quite unique and one of the most “built in” designs we’ve ever seen.  The attention to detail used to create this cantilevered corner fireplace, including the use of a continuous stone slab for both the firebox and continuing on along the entire media wall, as well as the absence of any glass partition between the room and gas flame makes this unit and the stone wall around it a work of art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/07/07/Modern%20Stacked%20Stone%20Feature%20Wall%20Asheville.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Modern Stacked Stone Feature Wall in Asheville, NC&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stacked stone on opposing walls of this main living space creates a great contrast in texture that is often overlooked in modern design and helps direct focus towards the large glass wall and out beyond to the lake.  While natural light is in abundance in the space, the thoughtful use of up and down &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-school-pairing-lighting-fixtures-with-stone-veneer-for-amazing-results/&quot;&gt;lighting on this stone accent wall&lt;/a&gt; will give the room a lot of character in the evening hours that would have been lost without the lighting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/07/07/Modern%20Stacked%20Stone%20Pool%20Asheville.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Modern Stacked Stone Pool in Asheville,NC&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not to be overlooked is the small yet packed with features &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/summer-s-here-jump-into-these-amazing-pools-designed-with-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;stone lined relaxation pool&lt;/a&gt;.  This little space has it all – an infinity edge overlooking the lake, built in stepping stones that allow access to and from an isolated section of the rear patio, and a cool stacked stone accent wall with a large cut out to walk through.  What this pool lacks in size it more than makes up for in cutting edge design and features that flow perfectly into the rest of the outdoor space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here at Norstone, we’re fans of all different types of architecture and design, and we have products suitable for all styles and inspirations.  Our Charcoal XL panels were a great choice for the modern aesthetic of this project, but a very closely related product, our Ochre XL panel, while using the same sizing and design, pairs well with a much more rustic design scheme. We have in house design experts ready to discuss your project and recommend products given your style.  Contact us today to start the process of using natural stone veneer and tile on your next job!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">We're incredibly impressed with the use of our Charcoal XL Stacked Stone veneer on this new construction modern lake home in Asheville, NC. Take a seat and let's look at some of the design features that make this project award worthy.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2017/07/07/Asheville%20NC%20Modern%20Stacked%20Stone%20Home.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Asheville%20NC%20Modern%20Stacked%20Stone%20Home%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Asheville%20NC%20Modern%20Stacked%20Stone%20Home%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Selecting the Right Installer for your Next Tile or Stone Project</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/selecting-the-right-installer-for-your-next-tile-or-stone-project/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Selecting the Right Installer for your Next Tile or Stone Project" /><published>2017-06-30T14:46:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-06-30T14:46:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/selecting-the-right-installer-for-your-next-tile-or-stone-project</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/selecting-the-right-installer-for-your-next-tile-or-stone-project/">&lt;p&gt;While all of our products are extremely &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-diy-infographic/&quot;&gt;DIY friendly&lt;/a&gt; and their installation can be mastered by most handy homeowners with minimal experience, we find that an increasing majority of our clients are looking to have professionals install their stone and tile.  For most, life is so busy that they put a lot of value on the time an installation would take, not to mention a job well done.  To ensure that job is indeed done well, we’ve put together a checklist to use to make sure you’re hiring the right installer for your next tile or stone project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;make-sure-youre-hiring-the-right-type-of-contractor&quot;&gt;Make sure you’re hiring the right type of contractor&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/30/Planter%20Box%20Stacked%20Stone%20Installation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;White Stacked Stone being installed on a curved planter box&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the often overlooked steps in finding the right installer for your next tile or stone project is actually making sure you’ve got the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/hiring-a-contractor-for-your-next-stone-project/&quot;&gt;right type of contractor for the job.&lt;/a&gt;  A lot of time stone projects create confusion because many clients think they should be working with a stone mason, when in fact the product might be made out of stone, but is installed like a tile, such as our Norstone Stacked Stone Rock Panels.  When in doubt, the manufacturer of the tile and stone product, or the reputable wholesaler or retailer that you are purchasing the material from should be able to recommend the right type of contractor to do the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;start-the-search-by-asking-your-network&quot;&gt;Start the search by asking your network&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/30/Houzz%20Header.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Screnshot of the header of the Houzz website&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In today’s world, the logical place to start asking for referrals for a quality installer is in both your online and offline social networks.  If that search bears little fruit, the design community Houzz is another great option to find qualified installers in your local area, and view the reviews that have been written about them and their work on the community.  If the tile or stone product is being purchased locally, the local wholesaler or retailer may or may not offer installation services, but certainly should be able to give you a few referrals to contractors reputable in the area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;qualify-the-installer-for-the-work&quot;&gt;Qualify the installer for the work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/30/Commercial%20Charcoal%20Stone%20Veneer%20Installers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Installers working on a commercial stone veneer installation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When interviewing a contractor for the project its important to qualify them as having the skills for the type of work involved.  If you’re working on a mosaic glass tile backsplash, ask them about their experience installing glass tile, and what kind of tools they have at their disposal for this type of installation.  Similarly, if your project involves natural stone tile, make sure the installer has worked with natural stone before.  Another great differentiatior among installers is going to be industry certifications.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/learning-the-best-practices-for-tile-and-stone-installations-by-the-tile-council-of-north-america/&quot;&gt;Certified Tile Installers&lt;/a&gt;, as tested and awarded by governing bodies like the Tile Council of North America, are almost always going to offer a superior installation leveraging the techniques learned during the certification process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-references&quot;&gt;Get References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Request and speak to as many references as possible provided by the installers you are considering.  Learn what kind of work the installer did for them and how long ago the work was completed.  Ask the references if there were any issues, big or small, before, during, or after installation and how the installer worked with them to resolve them.  Be wary of references that are dated or none of the references noted any kind of issues with the process and don’t be afraid to ask for more references.  Installers that do good work have great references, so if something doesn’t feel right with an installer’s references, definitely take that into consideration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-all-of-the-details-in-writing&quot;&gt;Get all of the details in writing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve selected an installer, get all the details in some form of written communication.  Email and text messaging is most common these days for smaller projects.  Formal contracts and / or service agreements should be expected for larger projects.  Use this an opportunity to make it clear about what the contractor is responsible for doing and what you, the client, are responsible for.  Things like substrate preparation and setting materials might vary from job to job, installer to installer, so make sure its clear before you get started.  Other details like payment schedule and warranty expectations should not be overlooked either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;make-yourself-available-during-the-installation&quot;&gt;Make yourself available during the installation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/30/DIY%20Bathtastic%20Stone%20Feature%20Wall-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre Stacked Stone Rock Panel Installation on DIY show Bathtastic&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s always a good idea to make yourself, or someone you trust to make decisions for you, available and present during the installation.  Very few professional installers enjoy a client hanging over them all the time, but checking in at the beginning of each day to make sure they have everything they need and any questions answered, as well as stopping in at various points throughout the day is a great way to build trust with your installer and ensure a successful outcome.  Use these visits to not only survey the work that’s already been done, but primarily to look ahead at where the install is going and cover any unique situations, like what type of corner trim should be used in a certain spot, or how the tile is going to be cut around an outlet cover to avoid having to rework any of those tricky spots later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;be-an-enthusiastic-reference&quot;&gt;Be an enthusiastic reference&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your installer did a great job and you’re satisfied with the work, let them know it!  If they are active on social media networks, especially Houzz, write a glowing review, or offer up your name and number to serve as a reference for future clients.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Making sure you've got the right installer for a tile or stone project is one of the most important parts of the whole job. Here's a deep dive into the steps you should be taking when finding your next tile or stone installer.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2017/06/30/DIY%20Bathtastic%20Stone%20Feature%20Wall.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22How%20to%20Pick%20The%20Right%20Installer%20for%20a%20Tile%20Project%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22An%20installer%20setting%20stone%20veneer%20in%20a%20bathroom%20feature%20wall%20%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Amazing Interior &amp;amp; Exterior Palm Beach Remodel</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/amazing-interior-exterior-palm-beach-remodel/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Amazing Interior &amp; Exterior Palm Beach Remodel" /><published>2017-06-25T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-06-25T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/amazing-interior-exterior-palm-beach-remodel</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/amazing-interior-exterior-palm-beach-remodel/">&lt;p&gt;When the photos of this recently completed remodel in Palm Beach, FL came across our desk we were excited to share them with our network and talk in a little more detail about some of the subtle things that make this project amazing.  This project is particularly compelling because they were able to use the stone in both &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/interiors/&quot;&gt;interior&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/exteriors/&quot;&gt;exterior applications&lt;/a&gt;, creating that consistent color pallet and design aesthetic throughout the entire space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/26/Ochre%20-%20Residential%20-%20Palm%20Beach%20-%20Exterior%201.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ochre Stacked Stone on Residential Garage in Palm Beach&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting on the street facing exterior, the Ochre Rock Panel is cleverly used on the detached garage.  The garage is quite large by itself with 3 wide stalls, two of which are covered with the stone, which then extends out towards the street in a smaller but still rectangular overhang, creating the illusion of a larger garage, and also doing a good job of creating depth on a home that is set far back from the street.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/26/Ochre%20-%20Residential%20-%20Palm%20Beach%20-%20Exterior%202.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ochre Stacked Stone on breezeway in Palm Beach&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next thing that really catches our eye is the fantastic use of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stone-veneer-columns-norstone-classroom-series/&quot;&gt;corner units used on the columns&lt;/a&gt; of the breezeway which connects the garage and the house.  Norstone’s exclusive finger joint method corners really shine through in a detail like this where a natural looking corner is required.  Outside we also love the color match between the stone and the acid stained concrete driveway, as well as the mid century modern looking cut flagstone used on the entryway and steps.  A subtle detail on the exterior not to be missed is the stone veneer used as an accent below the upper windows creating that consistent exterior look between the garage, breezeway, and main house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/26/Ochre%20-%20Residential%20-%20Palm%20Beach%20-%20Feature%20Wall%201-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ochre Stone Veneer Floor to Ceiling Feature Wall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the interior, a blade wall bisects the main house in half longways and is covered floor to vaulted ceiling in stacked stone.  When the design trend is to often go dark with wood flooring, we love this client’s choice of going light on the floors, post and beam work, as well as the expansive paneled ceiling.  Along with the great natural light in this area, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-color-series-designing-ochre-blend/&quot;&gt;lighter tones of our Ochre Blend&lt;/a&gt; really shine through giving the living area a vibrant feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/26/Ochre%20-%20Residential%20-%20Palm%20Beach%20-%20Feature%20Wall%202.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ochre Stacked Stone Feature Wall with built in bookshelves&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The liberal use of built in shelving and niches in the blade wall is an artistic detail that should not go unnoticed.  The crafty use of various sizes and locations all with very geometric shapes goes along with the windows, doors, and hallways complimenting the linear geometry of the stacked stone panel system.  The consistency of a thin veneer panel system really shines through where a more traditional hand stacked loose veneer installation would end up looking less linear against the clean lines of the openings and breaks in the wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/26/Ochre%20-%20Residential%20-%20Palm%20Beach%20-%20Feature%20Wall%203.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ochre Exterior Columns on Patio in Palm Beach&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stone makes a final appearance &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-patios-designing-norstone-series/&quot;&gt;cladding the exterior columns on the back patio&lt;/a&gt;, an essential extension of any home in Florida. We love the way the subtle uplighting is tastefully done on the columns and the continued use of corner units on so many key areas, including the main entrance hallway into the living space, looks the best a corner possibly can using thin veneer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From start to finish this project’s consistent use of the Ochre Blend Rock Panel veneer does a great job of creating a cohesive look whether you’re out front parking the car, cooking dinner, or enjoying a balmy South Florida summer evening on the patio with a chilled drink in hand.  One of the great things about Norstone products is that they can be used both interior and exterior and more importantly, look great in either type of application.  Many exterior stone products look a little rough around the edges when used on the confines of an interior application, while some interior products shouldn’t even be used outside.  With a product like Norstone you can  focus on the overall design and create spaces that are truly interconnected like this amazing project we’ve happily shared with you. See what our customers are saying and don’t hesitate to contact Norstone today to discuss your next project and how our unique and exclusive natural stone veneer products can be a part of it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">At Norstone we're love great architecture, and this recently remodeled contemporary home in Palm Beach, FL checks all the boxes. Let's take a look at what makes this project where Norstone was used in both interior and exterior applications so special.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2017/06/26/Ochre%20-%20Residential%20-%20Palm%20Beach%20-%20Feature%20Wall%201.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Luxury%20Palm%20Beach%20Contemporary%20Remodel%20Stone%20Blade%20Wall%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Blade%20wall%20in%20a%20luxury%20Palm%20Beach%20contemporary%20home%20using%20Norstone%20Ochre%20Blend%20Rock%20Panels%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Learning the Best Practices for Tile and Stone Installations by the Tile Council of North America</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/learning-the-best-practices-for-tile-and-stone-installations-by-the-tile-council-of-north-america/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning the Best Practices for Tile and Stone Installations by the Tile Council of North America" /><published>2017-06-22T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-06-22T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/learning-the-best-practices-for-tile-and-stone-installations-by-the-tile-council-of-north-america</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/learning-the-best-practices-for-tile-and-stone-installations-by-the-tile-council-of-north-america/">&lt;p&gt;One of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/what-makes-norstone-different-a-lot/&quot;&gt;things about Norstone that makes our products unique&lt;/a&gt; from other veneers is that we really see and sell the product as a precision tile, as opposed to a more traditional masonry product.  Traditional masonry involves taking relatively basic inputs, like plain cut stone and mortar, and leveraging the talents of the installer to create something beautiful on a wall.  We leverage our ability to produce this same look, but in a thin panel format, which allows the product to be installed by a tile setter in lieu of a stone mason.  So we’re always interested in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/how-to-install-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;learning more about how tile is installed&lt;/a&gt; and common mistakes made installing tile so we can pass this information on to our clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This past week one of our distribution partners in South Florida was hosting a series of workshops during the evening hours where they invited an educator from the Tile Council of North America to come and speak to their customers, who are primarily tile contractors, about the right and wrong way to be installing tile.  During these workshops the TCNA also promoted their certification program which allows an installer to become a TCNA certified installer.  Here’s a quick highlight of some of the main topics covered in these workshops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/23/Tile%20Council%20of%20North%20America%20Logo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tile Council of North America Logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinset Coverage:  The amount of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/what-is-the-difference-between-different-types-of-thinset-and-what-s-the-best-thinset-for-stacked-stone-installations/&quot;&gt;tile thinset&lt;/a&gt; coverage that an installer gets on the back of a tile is one of the critical components of a quality installation.  The size of the trowel notch relative to the size of the tile and the way the thinset is troweled in straight lines and not swirls all contribute to making sure the back of the tile has adequate thinset coverage.  For a natural stone tile product like Norstone, the TCNA recommends 95% coverage, which is why its so important to follow our recommended installation practice of back buttering each panel and using a 1/2” square notch when installing.  Insufficient coverage can lead to the failure of the installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/23/Tile%20Thinset%20Coverage-min.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Tile with good thinset coverage on the back&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expansion Joints: During the workshop the TCNA educator did a great demonstration showing how the expansion of a tile or surrounding substrate by as a little as the width of a penny can cause tiles to buckle.  Norstone recommends perimeter expansion joints in all installations to ensure that as the installation, including the stone, substrate, and wall system, expand and contract according to the local environmental conditions, everything stays stable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/23/Tile%20Expansion%20Joint%20Failure-min.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tiles that have buckled due to lack of an expansion joint&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installer’s Responsibilities: A key takeaway the TCNA wanted to stress to the installers in the audience was that if the tile installation failed, even if the tile installer did everything correctly, it is still going to be the tile installers problem to handle.  For example, if a homeowner insists on not having a perimeter expansion joint because they want a tight look of tile against wall or floor, and the installation ends up failing, it looks bad on the installer.  Or if the framer on a job framed out a shower using treated wood, which contains moisture and will expand / contract over time, instead of regular kiln dried wood, the installation might fail and again the tile installer looks bad.  The TCNA stresses that its important for all tile installers to make sure every component of their installations are done correctly because as the finishing surface the first thing people will assume was done wrong on a failed installation is the tile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certified Installers:  One of the more interesting industry level topics coming out of this week’s workshops was the concept that the industry is shifting and starting to put a premium on certified installers.  The process is starting at the specification level, where architects and designers that are are choosing what products get used on their projects, are beginning to include in the specification document that the installer must be certified.  Specifiers have long recommended that the product be installed by a “professional” tile setter, but with the added nuance of that professional being “certified” only serves to increase the value of the certification to installers and is something to look for when &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/hiring-a-contractor-for-your-next-stone-project/&quot;&gt;hiring a contractor for your next stone or tile job&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/23/Certified%20Tile%20Installer%20Logo-min.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Certifiled Tile Installer Logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike many of our peers in the industry, the background of the leadership team at Norstone doesn’t include any professional “bucket and trowel” experience, however that hasn’t stopped us from vigorously learning and consulting with industry leaders over the past decade to develop the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/how-to-install-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;best practices for installing Norstone products&lt;/a&gt;.  This week’s TCNA workshops were a great reminder that while it could seem simple on the surface, installing tile is much more than it seems and a wide ranging variety of factors need to be taken into consideration when doing so.  So whether you have questions about a Norstone installation you have planned for the future, or are in the middle of one right now, don’t hesitate to contact us and speak with our technical service team or email us your question and we’ll get back with you right away.  Until then – happy tiling!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2017/06/23/NTCA%20Tile%20Presentation-min.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22NTCA%20Tile%20Installation%20Workshop%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22NTCA%20Tile%20Instatllation%20Workshop%20at%20D&amp;B%20Tile%20in%20South%20Florida%20%22%7D" /></entry></feed>