<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.1.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://www.norstoneusa.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://www.norstoneusa.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-07-25T20:02:33+00:00</updated><id>http://www.norstoneusa.com/</id><title>Norstone | Natural Stone Veneer | Natural Stone Products</title><subtitle>New dimensions in natural stone.</subtitle><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><entry><title>Norstone Industry Series - Marble Tile Backsplash</title><link href="http://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-industry-series-marble-tile-backsplash.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Norstone Industry Series - Marble Tile Backsplash" /><published>2016-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-industry-series----marble-tile-backsplash</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-industry-series-marble-tile-backsplash.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:16px;font-weight:lighter;letter-spacing:1px&quot;&gt;Any time it comes to decorating a kitchen - appliances, cabinets and the hard surfaces are where all of the fun is.&lt;/span&gt; And come to think of it, that’s about all a kitchen really is period. It’s also foot to foot the most expensive room to design, build or remodel, so we are talking about a major investment even if it’s the only space you are working on. At Norstone, we work with our customers everyday on backsplash projects that range in looks from rustic, using our &lt;a href=&quot;/products/rock-panels/ochre/&quot;&gt;Ochre Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt;, to uber – modern, with our &lt;a href=&quot;/products/modern-wall-tile/&quot;&gt;Basalt Interlocking Tiles&lt;/a&gt;. A trend we’re seeing lots of kitchens using is to extend their countertop surface to the backsplash. This can be used to create a more dynamic and bold looking kitchen, create a durable backsplash, and highlight the beauty of the material on a vertical surface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Marble-Tile-Backsplash---Onyx.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;Of the thousands of choices of slab sized natural stone that could be used for this type of application, including soapstone, slate, onyx, limestone, there are three stones that completely dominate all other materials in popularity when it comes to use as a kitchen backsplash - granite, marble and quartz. Even though design styles are constantly changing and evolving, granite, quartz, or marble tile backsplashes always have a huge fan base as favorites amongst designers, architects and builders. Of the big 3, one stands out as the leader when it comes to overall quality - quartz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Marble-Tile-Backsplash---Quartz.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;A large part in quartz being such a top quality go-to material is its incredible durability and highly sought after characteristics. Compared to a granite or marble tile backsplash, quartzite is actually much more resistant to stains and acids (etching), more scratch resistant, heat resistant, and easier to care for overall which means less maintenance and more economical over time. Quartz also requires less sealing over time than a granite or marble tile backsplash and has a much more uniform and pure look over all. And one of my personal favorite reasons to love quartz is that it doesn’t harbor bacteria – a clean kitchen is a healthy kitchen! That’s just the short list, but all powerful reasons to consider this wonderful material when designing a kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Marble-Tile-Backsplash---Quartz2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt;In comparison to a marble tile backsplash, quartz outperforms in the maintenance department. Marble tends to stain easily due to being very porous, and thus requires a higher rate of sealing than quartz. A marble tile backsplash can also easily scratch, and does not fare very well when left in contact with acidic foods or liquids since they can eat away at the surface finish.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary>Granite, Marble, Quartz – the big three when it comes to high end stone countertop material. Ever wondered how these products would hold up when you turn that stone 90 degrees and put in on the backsplash? The answers might surprise you!</summary></entry><entry><title>Norstone Classroom Series - Ceramic Wall Tile – Color Variation in Natural Stone vs Manmade Tile Products</title><link href="http://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-classroom-series-ceramic-wall-tile.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Norstone Classroom Series - Ceramic Wall Tile – Color Variation in Natural Stone vs Manmade Tile Products" /><published>2016-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-classroom-series-ceramic-wall-tile</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-classroom-series-ceramic-wall-tile.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:16px;font-weight:lighter;letter-spacing:1px&quot;&gt;If you’re thinking that a hard surface is a good option for your next wall covering project,&lt;/span&gt; one of the first decisions you’ll likely end up making is whether to go with a natural product, like a stone veneer, or a manmade product, like a porcelain or ceramic wall tile. One of the biggest differences between the two is with respect to color variation, so let’s dig a little deeper into each of these products to understand what the advantages are for each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Ceramic-Wall-Tile---Natural-Stone-Veneer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;From a color variation standpoint, natural stone is almost always admired for its inherently unique characteristics. Whether it’s subtle variation in the color of the stone, veining, or faceting, there are a number of things that make each and every piece of natural stone unique. It is this uniqueness that creates a draw and puts value on natural stone products in the marketplace. At Norstone, we encourage our customers to embrace the uniqueness of natural stone and the color variations it brings in products like our &lt;a href=&quot;/products/rock-panels/ochre/&quot;&gt;Ochre Blend&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/products/rock-panels/ivory/&quot;&gt;Ivory&lt;/a&gt; Rock Panels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The flip side of the argument with natural stone is that some people will be looking for a less varied, more consistent look. While this person might be enamored with the idea of having a natural stone backsplash, the idea of rose colored vein running through their White Quartz keeps them up at night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Ceramic-Wall-Tile---Kitchen-Backsplash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt;For those unable or unwilling to accept the color variations in natural stone, manmade tile products like porcelain and ceramic wall tile are a great alternative. Since these products are manmade, there is control over the output in terms of color and any other variation. Ceramic wall tile buyers can be reasonably assured that when they buy tile from a quality manufacturer, that the product will be consistent from a color, dimensional, and build standpoint. However, just like natural stone, manmade tile products will vary from batch to batch, so always be sure to order enough to complete your job and account for waste when working on any tile or stone project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Ceramic-Wall-Tile---Natural-Stone-Look.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;In general the subtlety and uniqueness that only Mother Nature can provide is more desirable in the stone and tile industry, and most people see and appreciate the natural beauty it creates. In fact is so desirable that the manmade tile industry has spent millions on creating floor and wall tile products that are made to look like natural stone. Just stop in your local tile shop and look at the ceramic wall tile section and you’ll see a variety of tiles made to mimic natural stone. However, manmade tile products like porcelain and ceramic wall tile are a good alternative for someone needing a more consistent color range to work from. So wherever you fall in the spectrum of color variation, know that there is a good product out there for your next wall covering project and plenty of good people at Norstone and your local tile shops that can help guide you through the selection process.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary>There are many differences between manmade tile products, like porcelains and ceramics, as compared to natural stone. One of the most noticeable is color variation – something that can be tightly controlled when tile is manufactured versus something Mother Nature dictates when it comes to natural stone. Learn more about why color can vary and figure out what type of product works best for you.</summary></entry><entry><title>Norstone Classroom Series - Backsplash Trends</title><link href="http://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-classroom-series-backsplash-trends.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Norstone Classroom Series - Backsplash Trends" /><published>2014-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-classroom-series---backsplash-trends</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-classroom-series-backsplash-trends.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:16px;font-weight:lighter;letter-spacing:1px&quot;&gt;When you walk into a kitchen, one of the first things you notice is the backsplash.&lt;/span&gt; It is the focal point of the room – what everything is centered around. It can tie together your cabinets, countertops and bring forth the general aesthetic of the space. Today, your backsplash options are endless. Some might be fads that fade fast, but exploring the current trends is inspiring, exciting, and the first step in finding what you’ll fall in love with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Backsplash-Tile-Designs---E&amp;amp;S.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;One trend that we are seeing, and not just in backsplashes but throughout whole house design, is earth friendly products. Renewable, recycled and environmentally safe products make for a greener house, and we are not talking about the color! You can even make sure your backsplash is green by using a product such as these &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eandstile.net/&quot;&gt;barnwood tiles&lt;/a&gt; from E&amp;amp;S Tile. These unique backsplash tile designs are made from recycled barnwood gathered from 80 year old barns and distilleries. They are finished with a low VOC ceramic coating for easy cleaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Backsplash-Tile-Designs---Stainless-Steel.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt;Another trend that we are noticing is stainless steel backsplashes. Stainless steel is as efficient and low maintenance as it is stylish. It offers a number of advantages, ranging from durability to the fact that it can be integrated into just about any kitchen design to coordinate with most appliances. Like the appliances, the stainless steel backsplash tile design is sleek but refined and a great option for anyone looking to add both visual interest and efficiency to their kitchen.  Stainless steel is available in both tiles as well as larger cut to fit sheets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Backsplash-Tile-Designs---Subway-Tile.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;When talking about backsplash trends, you can’t leave out the trusty, long loved subway tile. With the revival of vintage and shabby chic, the subway tile is making a comeback. The classic, understated look of a subway tile is extremely versatile. It can be paired with just about any kitchen style, from traditional to hyper-modern. The subway tile comes in an endless variety of materials, colors and textures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Backsplash-Tile-Designs---Stacked-Stone.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt;Another great trend in backsplashes is the use of natural stone. Technically this could fall into the earth friendly category, but they are so unique and beautiful, I thought they should stand on their own. Of course you can go with a traditional slate or travertine tile, but what we are seeing today is the use of drystacked ledge stones like Norstone’s [Rock Panels]/products/stacked-stone-cladding/)&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 12px;&quot;&gt;. These panels take the old and make it new. They bring the outdoors in while providing a versatile pallet that coordinates well with traditional or modern design. They provide rawness to the space that really fits in a kitchen.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A backsplash is a chance to really bring out the personality of a kitchen. It is the finishing touch, the cherry on the top. Research the various materials that are out there and find the one that best fits you and the space and most importantly, have fun with it!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary>Think of your kitchen or bath backsplash as a canvas where you can express your own creativity or embrace the latest trends in backsplash tile design, without the same cost and construction commitment as other elements of the space, like cabinets and countertops. Let&#39;s explore some more trends in backsplash design that might get you in the remodeling mood!</summary></entry><entry><title>Norstone Classroom Series - Installing Norstone Around Outlets</title><link href="http://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-classroom-series-installing-norstone-around-outlets.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Norstone Classroom Series - Installing Norstone Around Outlets" /><published>2014-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-classroom-series---installing-norstone-around-outlets</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-classroom-series-installing-norstone-around-outlets.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/norstone-classroom-series-installing-norstone-around-outlets.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Stone-Veneer-Backsplash-Blog.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Stacked-Stone-Backsplash-Bathroom.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-size:16px;font-weight:lighter;letter-spacing:1px&quot;&gt;Norstone Rock Panels are a great option for a unique stacked stone backsplash in your kitchen or bath.&lt;/span&gt; With a range of colors to choose from, your &lt;a href=&quot;/gallery/application/backsplashes/&quot;&gt;backsplash&lt;/a&gt;can either serve as the perfect complement or accent feature in the space. One of the questions we hear a lot when working with our customers is how to work with the stone around electrical outlets and light switches. Here’s a quick rundown of what we’ve found most helpful when addressing those breaks in your backsplash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Modern-Stacked-Stone-Backsplash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Depth&lt;/strong&gt; - the first thing you’ll want to consider is the depth of your current outlets and light switches against the stone. &lt;a href=&quot;/products/stacked-stone-cladding/&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;Norstone Rock Panel&lt;/a&gt;s will vary between about .75” and 1.75” thick, so a common solution to minimize the recess of the existing outlet against the face of the stone is to add a 1/2” outlet box extender, which will screw into your existing wall box and provide you with new mounting holes to remount the outlets and switches. Most of the time outlets and switches will remain slightly recessed of the face of the stone, but larger extenders can be used to position them closer to flush with the stone face. Extenders are available in the electrical section of most hardware stores and remember whenever you are working with electricity, shut off the power to that switch / outlet first and use a tester to make sure the outlet isn’t powered prior to beginning work. When in doubt. always consult a licensed electrician.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Stacked-Stone-Backsplash-Outlet-Detail.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cuts&lt;/strong&gt; - the easiest way to cut a hole in a stacked stone backsplash for an outlet or light switch is to have a one panel terminate into the side of the outlet, and cut the opening out of the adjoining piece. If you look closely at the picture to the right, you’ll see the switch buts up on the right side against a full panel, and then the opening for the switch has been cut out of a second panel which goes above, below, and continues along to the left of the switch. This method is recommended since it only requires a fairly simple cut out of one panel. An alternative option is to cut the outlet hole out right from the middle of a panel, generally using a hand held angle grinder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; - once the cuts are made and the stacked stone backsplash installed around the outlets, the final step is finishing the outlets and switches with outlet covers. Existing outlet covers can always be used, or a variety of covers can be sourced from online merchants in various finishes including metal and stone, which could be used to accent or blend into the installation. If you’ve chosen to extend the outlets to have them sit close to flush with the stone, your finishing steps might also include some precision chiseling or detail work with an angle grinder to get the covers to sit flush against the face of the stone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a stacked stone backsplash is on your list of must haves, don’t let the prospect of working around the outlets and switches deter you! Using some basic stone and tile installation principles, and a few tricks unique to the product, you’ll be on your way to enjoying your backsplash in no time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary>Whether it&#39;s charging up your phone or setting the mood with lighting, outlets and switches are a necessary and important part of many kitchen and bath backsplashes. However, when it comes time to renovate, figuring out how to work your new surface material around them might be more than you bargained for! This week&#39;s article is a great tutorial on how to work around outlets when installing a stacked stone backsplash and many of the lessons can be applied to other similar surfaces as well.</summary></entry><entry><title>The Basics of Designing With Travertine</title><link href="http://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/the-basics-of-designing-with-travertine.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Basics of Designing With Travertine" /><published>2014-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/the-basics-of-designing-with-travertine</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/the-basics-of-designing-with-travertine.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/the-basics-of-designing-with-travertine.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Travertine-Tile-Blog.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Travertine-Tile-French-Pattern.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-size:16px;font-weight:lighter;letter-spacing:1px&quot;&gt;You probably see Travertine everyday without knowing it.&lt;/span&gt; It is used for flooring, wall features, pool decks, walkways, steps, fireplaces, patios and even driveways. Travertine is Limestone that has been put under immense pressure for a long time. Travertine eventually morphs into Marble if that pressure continues to be applied. It is available in numerous grades, finishes &amp;amp; formats. While Travertine can be made into pavers, its most common format is tiles. Travertine tiles themselves come in a variety of cuts, patterns, shapes and sizes, ranging from 4” x 4”, 6” x 6”, 12” x 12” all the way up to 24” x 24”. The reason you see this material everywhere is because of it versatility. It is sure to fit any project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Travertine-Tile-Bathroom.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt;Travertine tiles are one of the most frequently used materials in modern architecture. Since the color is neutral beige with some variation, it coordinates nicely with other basics and even plays well with fun pops of color. Travertine tiles can either be the star of the show or can fade into the background, allowing other aspects of the space to shine. Some of the knocks on Travertine are that it can scratch easily and can be susceptible to staining if not sealed properly, even via the mildest of acids like vinegar and orange juice. Polished and sealed Travertine can also be slippery when wet. However, most often any problem related to Travertine is often a result of the incorrect finish being used for the application. Always consult a flooring expert when selecting any type of tile to make sure the tile’s physical properties and attributes meet the demands of the space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Travertine-Tile-Pool-Deck.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;Due to their simplicity, Travertine tiles pair well with other natural materials. For example in the pictured application, Norstone’s &lt;a href=&quot;/products/rock-panels/white/&quot;&gt;natural stone rock panels in White&lt;/a&gt; are used as a waterline tile and spa surround in this mid century South Florida home. The light colored tumbled travertine used for the pool decking and coping is a popular choice for this type of application because of its texture and color pallet. At Norstone, we see travertine frequently paired with our White and &lt;a href=&quot;/products/rock-panels/ivory/&quot;&gt;Ivory Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt;, particularly when a customer is looking for a finishing piece, such as a cap for a landscape knee wall, or the flat hearth surface of a freshly renovated fireplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, Travertine is a tried and true friend when it comes to decorating and remodeling. It is a safe, no fail option if you are overwhelmed with the choices and not sure what to choose. Travertine tiles provide a neutral pallet to build off of and design around. Or, if you apply the principle of multiplied simplicity and cover the walls and floors with it, such as in a bathroom, it can be overwhelmingly beautiful on its own.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary>Sometimes as ubiquitous as it is beautiful, Travertine really is its own segment in the natural stone industry. When you start hearing words like tumbled, polished, honed or filled you know you&#39;re entering a world of light earthy tones with uses as diverse as the stone itself. Come learn the basics of this unique natural stone and why it might just be the perfect selection for your next project.</summary></entry><entry><title>Norstone Industry Series - Tumbled Stone</title><link href="http://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-industry-series-tumbled-stone.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Norstone Industry Series - Tumbled Stone" /><published>2014-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-industry-series---tumbled-stone</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-industry-series-tumbled-stone.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/norstone-industry-series-tumbled-stone.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Tumbled-Stone-Blog.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Tumbled-Stone-Pavers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-size:16px;font-weight:lighter;letter-spacing:1px&quot;&gt;In today’s design world there are practically no limits to what can be used as a decorative surface material.&lt;/span&gt; Metal, glass, wood, and stone are just a few primary categories of materials, each with a multitude of different finishes that they can be prepared in. For today’s topic, let’s concentrate on stone and more specifically tumbled stone. Tumbled stone’s popularity comes from the fact that it helps create the weathered old world look that adds an air of classiness and establishment to any project, and lends itself towards a variety of residential and commercial applications including kitchens, bathrooms, offices, retail and hospitality projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Tumbled-Stone-Shower-Floor.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt; Tumbled stone products start life as large stones that have been quarried, rough cut, and shipped to fabricators who cut down those large blocks of stone into smaller slabs, pavers, or tiles. The stone is then placed into large drums along with grit, crushed stones, water, and other abrasives and spun according to the fabricator’s “recipe” for what look they are hoping to achieve. Everything inside the drum will rub and wear against the stone until the fabricator gets the desired tumbled effect or finish they want. Post tumbling, much can be done to diversify this design style. Larger stones can be cut into smooth rounded milky tiles or smaller stones like gemstones and river rocks can be placed onto backers and paired with other materials such as glass for a more colorful finish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Tumbed-Stone-with-Rock-Panels.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt;The old-world charm of tumbled stone offers the opportunity to create a professional look with a very unique style for interior and exterior projects. These classic tile or rounded stone accent surfaces offer meticulous artistry and design applications limited only by your imagination. The myriad of color choices, the patterns, and the materials can be combined to build a true work of art that will accent any space whether traditional or modern. For the team here at Norstone, the tumbled look is something we appreciate very much. Being in direct contrast to the sharp, geometric lines of our &lt;a href=&quot;/products/stacked-stone-cladding/&quot;&gt;Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/products/modern-wall-tile/&quot;&gt;Basalt Tiles&lt;/a&gt;, it expands our horizons on different ways stone can be finished and how different finishes can be paired to achieve a seamless look, such as the photo you see here where our Ivory Rock Panel is paired with a tumbled travertine to border a pizza oven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with any trend, the tumbled stone look is bound to ebb and flow from the fancy of designers and trend setters in the natural stone industry. Fabricators and manufacturers will continue to push forward with new twists on the tumbled look and more efficient ways to process. Designers will then find unique ways to use it to create environments pleasing to their clients. So next time a classic old world design project happens across your desk, think about finding a spot to use tumbled stone, from the floors to the walls and everything in between!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary>Tumbled Stone is to polished marble as those $500 &quot;vintage&quot; designer jeans are to a brand new pair of Levis. Have no fear Norstonians, this isn&#39;t SAT English - but it is our latest Blog where we take a closer look at what all the fuss is about when you take a perfectly good stone and make it look old.</summary></entry><entry><title>Small Can Be Beautiful Too</title><link href="http://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/small-can-be-beautiful-too.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Small Can Be Beautiful Too" /><published>2014-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/small-can-be-beautiful-too</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/small-can-be-beautiful-too.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/small-can-be-beautiful-too.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Small-is-Beautiful-Design.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Austrian house is a fully-furnished, fully-functional home tucked away into a hillside with absolutely breathtaking views of the surrounding mountains. The structure blends the comforts of a traditional house with the futurism of contemporary design. Set on stilts, it is built to maximize spectacular views while minimizing the environmental impact of its construction, a design choice rarely seen outside of beach communities. Windows, both small and large, provide light to every part of the building without sacrificing personal privacy, a consideration that’s often missed in the design of compact houses. The interior of the house is fairly minimal in style, dominated by a single wood finish and accented by clever little details in each room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Small-is-beautiful-Austria-House(1).jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as we’d love to find a place for some our &lt;a href=&quot;/products/modern-wall-tile/&quot;&gt;Basalt IL Tiles&lt;/a&gt; or maybe even the &lt;a href=&quot;/products/stacked-stone-cladding/&quot;&gt;Rock Panel Collection&lt;/a&gt; on this puppy, it looks pretty positively perfect just the way it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/ufogel05.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/ufogel08.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/ufogel01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary>A small home made almost completely of larch wood in Austria dazzles us with its imaginative composition of traditionalism and futurism. Simply stunning, come check this gem out.</summary></entry><entry><title>Have A Seat, Let’s Talk About Slate Tile</title><link href="http://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/have-a-seat-lets-talk-about-slate.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Have A Seat, Let&#39;s Talk About Slate Tile" /><published>2013-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/have-a-seat-lets-talk-about-slate</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/have-a-seat-lets-talk-about-slate.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/have-a-seat-lets-talk-about-slate.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Slate-Stone-Blog.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Slate-Tile-Norstone-Firepit.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-size:16px;font-weight:lighter;letter-spacing:1px&quot;&gt; Slate is a generalized term in the natural stone industry, and can take on a whole lot of different meanings depending on who you talk to.&lt;/span&gt; Many people refer to any naturally cleft stone in the grey - brown color family, be it for flooring or wall cladding, as slate. Norstone’s &lt;a href=&quot;/products/rock-panels/charcoal&quot;&gt;Charcoal&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/products/rock-panels/ochre/&quot;&gt;Ochre Blend&lt;/a&gt; Rock Panels are often confused for slate, although neither of them actually contain slate, which is a dense, but soft, fine grained metamorphic rock. Slate itself can vary in terms of its physical properties depending on what quarrying region it comes from, which includes both North and South America, and Asia. Although wildly popular for both interior and exterior uses, slate does have its limitations, including certain varieties that tend to be softer, thus more susceptible to scratching and flaking / powdering with use, as well as other varieties which have high absorption rates and shouldn’t be used for exterior applications in freeze / thaw climates. Always work with a knowledgeable stone expert when buying slate and discuss what you plan to use it for to make sure the type of slate you’re buying is a good match for the job. Once installed, there are a few easy tips to remember when maintaining slate tile and other natural stone tile products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing any natural stone owner or caretaker should do is consider sealing their stone. Water based sealers are going to be recommended for most slate tiles and other natural stone materials and not only afford the stone a layer of protection against the elements, but can also be used to achieve certain looks, including high gloss or “wet look” finishes. It’s important to test any natural stone sealer on a sample piece, off cut, or in an inconspicuous place on the installation to verify the results before applying the sealer over the entire application. Sealing will provide your slate tile or other natural stone tiles with the best pro-active protection available.  The photo below shows the difference between unsealed slate tile and tiles that have been sealed with a color enhancing sealer.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Slate-Tile-Sealer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Natural-Stone-Tile-Stain.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt;When the inevitable call for clean up does occur, be it a spilled glass of wine or junior dropping his bowl of spaghetti off his high-chair, the first and most important step is to take action as quickly as possible. Slate Tiles and most other natural stone tiles are porous and will soak up liquid spills. Immediately triage by wiping up the spill with a paper towel and then use either a detergent based cleaner or a specially formulated natural stone cleaner to tackle deep staining. Remember that slate tiles, depending on their origin, can be soft, so clean using a plastic bristle brush to avoid any surface scratching and most importantly do not use any acidic cleaners, including citrus based products, or scouring products which can cause damage to the stone. It’s always going to be a good idea to reseal an area that just underwent a thorough cleaning as the cleaning likely removed or greatly decreased the efficacy of the sealer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We expect slate tile and other natural stone tile products to continue to be sought after for the unique one of a kind natural look that can’t be re-created in a factory. With a few simple steps and knowledge of how to care for these types of products, slate and other natural stone floor and wall coverings not only make sense but become very appealing to the discerning customer looking to set their project apart. So go ahead and use a natural stone tile for your next project - you’ll thank us later!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary>Slate tile and other sedimentary based stone tiles are wildly popular due to their range of colors, ease of use, and in many instances, great value. While these products aren&#39;t as durable as most ceramics or porcelain tiles, slate tile and other stone tiles can be easily maintained with a few simple steps and will offer the uniquely natural qualities that a manufactured product just won&#39;t have. Read on for some tips about caring for your slate tile and other sedimentary based stone tiles.</summary></entry><entry><title>A Classic Never Dies…We Heart You, Subway Tile</title><link href="http://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/a-classic-never-dies-...-how-to-design-with-subway-tile.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Classic Never Dies...We Heart You, Subway Tile" /><published>2013-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/a-classic-never-dies-...-how-to-design-with-subway-tile</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/a-classic-never-dies-...-how-to-design-with-subway-tile.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/a-classic-never-dies-...-how-to-design-with-subway-tile.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Natural-Stone-Subway-Tile.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Gorgeous-White-Subway-Tile-is-a-classic.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:16px;font-weight:lighter;letter-spacing:1px&quot;&gt;We recently bought a home and it is a fixer upper.&lt;/span&gt; My husband and I are already dreaming about the laundry list of projects we want to tackle. The first up is the bathroom. When brainstorming ideas for the design of the space, the various materials and textures to consider, my suggestion for the shower was subway tiles. They are classic, easy to clean, and affordable. However, my husband’s automated response was “Subway tiles? They are so boring!” Little does he know the world of Subway tiles that exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subway tiles have been popular since the early 1900’s when they were used in New York to decorate the walls of the underground rail stations. When they were first introduced, the tiles were made out of ceramic and came in one size, 3” x 6”. They quickly captured the public’s imagination and moved from the subway into the bathrooms and kitchens of prewar houses for both practical and aesthetic reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, the subway tile has endured as a favorite for almost a century. Yet, this classic has evolved with times. Subway tiles are now produced in a variety of sizes &amp;amp; configurations. Manufacturers often use the term now to describe any rectangular tile with a length twice its height, from 4-by-8-inch planks to 1-by-2 mosaics, and even some tiles (such as contemporary 2-by-8 strips) that don’t share the original’s proportions at all. What’s great about the various sizes now offered is that it allows you to use the material and find the proper scale for the desired space. For example, if you are covering a large area such as a mudroom feature wall, the 4” x 12” tiles would look less busy and are fitting for a big space. If working on a backsplash or a small fireplace surround, the 3” x 6” or even 2” x 6” tiles would be more appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only has the definition &amp;amp; size of the tile changed with the times, so has the material. In addition to ceramic, subway tiles are now also made in glass with various finishes. This innovation gives the classic tile a modern twist. It mixes a bit of the old with the new and provides an array of colors that partner well with just about any style of decor. Glass subway tiles also hold up better than the original ceramic. The old ceramic style of tile would degrade over time from water and would start to wear quickly. Glass tiles do not have this problem as it is impervious to water which makes it ideal to use in bathrooms, kitchens, and pools. Norstone has their own take on a subway tile with their &lt;a href=&quot;/products/modern-wall-tile/&quot;&gt;Basalt Interlocking Tile&lt;/a&gt; Product, which features similar product ratios in a unique mesh mounted system, allowing for quicker installation and a modern twist on a classic look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Black-Subway-Tile-Norstone.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, after showing my husband how the subway tile has been around for so long yet evolved with the times with an endless array of options, he is now on board. I simply explained, subway tiles are like a good pair of black pants. With a timeless silhouette and versatile pallet, they will be in style forever!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary>We recently bought a home and it is a fixer upper. My husband and I are already dreaming about the laundry list of projects we want to tackle. The first up is the bathroom. When brainstorming ideas for the design of the space, the various materials and textures to consider, my suggestion for the shower was subway tiles. They are classic, easy to clean, and affordable. However, my husband&#39;s automated response was &quot;Subway tiles? They are so boring!&quot; Little does he know the world of Subway tiles that exist...</summary></entry><entry><title>How To Design Your Next Mosaic Tile Backsplash</title><link href="http://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-design-your-next-mosaic-tile-backsplash.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How To Design Your Next Mosaic Tile Backsplash" /><published>2013-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-design-your-next-mosaic-tile-backsplash</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-design-your-next-mosaic-tile-backsplash.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/how-to-design-your-next-mosaic-tile-backsplash.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Mosaic-Tile-Backsplash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Mosaic-Tile-Backsplash---Norstone-Charcoal.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-size:16px;font-weight:lighter;letter-spacing:1px&quot;&gt;I’m sure we can all agree that the layout of a kitchen is extremely important.&lt;/span&gt; The work flow must always be considered for maximum efficiency and comfort while preparing meals. It is also extremely important to feel visually comfortable in order to be able to fully enjoy what is generally known as the busiest room in the house. In this Norstone Designer Series blog we will be discussing the use of mosaic tile options for the kitchen, which would primarily be used for backsplashes. To start with a little background, mosaic originated as the art of creating images with an assemblage of small pieces of colored glass, stone, or other materials. Mosaics are rooted in ancient times and are one of mankind’s oldest art forms.  They continue to endure as a globally popular and, with today’s technology, economical form of interior decoration. Most mosaics are made of small, flat, multi shaped pieces of stone or glass that comes in many different colors, known as Tesserae, but mosaics, especially floor mosaics, may also be made of small rounded pieces of stone and called “pebble mosaics”. With modern day building supplies, design materials and tools, the choices for mosaic patterns, colors and application ideas are virtually endless. The use of ceramics, stained glass and metal are part of the list of the mosaic family of products as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Mosaic-Tile-Backsplash---Bubbles.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt;Mosaic tile backsplashes are a popular feature in current kitchen design. One drawback with authentic piece by piece hand laid mosaics is that they are time consuming to install and require an artist’s touch to transform individual pieces into what eventually becomes art. The talent level needed for this type of application is extremely high and should be strictly handled by professionals that have lots of training and experience at this method of installation, which increases the cost and time needed for installation. Tile manufacturers are meeting consumer’s demands for mosaic applications by pre-mounting the mosaics onto various backing systems, including mesh and plastic. By pre-mounting the mosaic to a backer, the mosaic can be installed in standard size sections, similar to any other wall tile, and will often interlock with neighboring sections. While a pre-mounted mosaic tile product might not have the “hand laid” feel of traditional mosaic, they are much easier to install and are often tackled as a DIY project by homeowners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Mosaic-Tile-Backsplash---Basalt-IL-Grey.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;A great example of a mosaic tile backsplash that is pre-mounted on a mesh backing system is Norstone’s &lt;a href=&quot;/products/modern-wall-tile/&quot;&gt;Basalt Interlocking Tile&lt;/a&gt;. This tile offers a sleek consistent interlocking strip pattern already set and staggered for you on a mesh backer, eliminating any of the guess work involved in creating the desired pattern. The tiles comes in two trendy grey toned colors, ash gray and ebony, sporting a geometric look in a sleek modern package. They offer a refined, luxurious finish, smooth to the touch and oozing elegance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/Mosaic-Tile-Backsplash---Norstone-Ebony-Basalt.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt;With the many choices present in the design of a kitchen, including cabinetry and countertops, the backsplash is one the main surfaces that can give your design a “pop”, be it through the use of bold colors, textures, or patterns. Trends in mosaic tile backsplashes are dynamic and always changing and while traditional mosaics will continue to offer up a timeless look, pre-mounted mosaics offer an attractive alternative to achieve a similar look with the benefit of an easier, more cost effective installation. Whichever direction you decide to go when you create a mosaic tile backsplash always try to have fun and make it your own. The goal should be to make this space comfortable and appealing as well as beautiful and functional - and the backsplash is your canvas to do so. Happy designing!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary>A kitchen without a backsplash is like a car without windshield wipers - it can work some of the time, but when things get wet, watch out! A popular finish in today&#39;s kitchen design is the use of mosaic tiles backsplashes, made from a variety of materials including tile, glass, stone, even metal. Come with us and explore the difference between traditional hand laid mosaics and today&#39;s pre-mounted systems and see how a mosaic tile backsplash might be a good fit for your next kitchen remodel.</summary></entry></feed>