<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-07-12T16:25:31+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/</id><title type="html">Norstone USA</title><subtitle>New dimensions in natural stone.</subtitle><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><entry><title type="html">How to Pick the Perfect Flooring to Complement a Stacked Stone Wall</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/flooring-for-stacked-stone/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Pick the Perfect Flooring to Complement a Stacked Stone Wall" /><published>2017-07-12T12:02:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-12T12:02:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-pair-flooring-with-stacked-stone</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/flooring-for-stacked-stone/">&lt;p&gt;Flooring is a detail not be overlooked when working on a stacked stone wall project.  The right flooring  can complement the wall from a color standpoint, either as matching or contrasting in shade, as well as in pattern and texture.  Let’s take a look at some of our favorite &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/project/&quot;&gt;stone veneer projects&lt;/a&gt; and how the right flooring was used to enhance the overall look of the space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/07/12/White%20Stacked%20Stone%20Modern%20Fireplace.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;White Stacked Stone Modern Fireplace with ventless insert&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This first project is a study in the classic contrast of black on white, two colors that pair well together in both a formal and modern way.  This particular space shows off the great texture and consistent color of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/rock-panels/white/&quot;&gt;White Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt;, which is contrasted beautifully with the stagger set large format black tiles.  A detail that is easily overlooked is the short “tile kick” that is used as a trim piece on the bottom couple inches of the wall, which helps transition the texture of the wall down to the smoothness of the floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/07/12/White%20Stone%20Veneer%20Hotel%20Lobby%20Fireplace%20Alberta.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;White Stacked Stone Modern Fireplace in Hotel Lobby Alberta Canada&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This next project also features another stunning White Rock Panel fireplace with dark flooring, but what we love the most about this space is the random patterned carpet that creates a wonderful contrast with the starkness of the multi story white fireplace.  A carpet with this type of design just won’t work with a patterned wall, resulting in a very “busy look”, but is the perfect complement to the modern glass and white stone backdrop of this hotel lobby in Alberta, Canada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/07/12/Basalt%203D%20Ash%20Grey%20Corner%20Fireplace%20Washington.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Basalt Grey Stone Veneer Panel on Corner Fireplace in bank lobby&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carpet sometimes gets a bad rap from homeowners because it can lack the overall durability of a hard surface like wood, stone, or tile, but the design community certainly embraces carpet for its ability to create a complex pattern or look that can’t be replicated on a hard surface.  This next project is a great example of that idea, with the carpet capturing the overall “beige” color pallete of the space while featuring a complex cross hatch pattern that meshes nicely with the clean line geometry and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-trends-when-it-comes-to-stone-smooth-is-in/&quot;&gt;smooth face of the Grey Basalt 3D Panels&lt;/a&gt; on this unique corner fireplace in the upper lobby of a bank in Washington state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/07/12/Ochre%20Stacked%20Stone%20Office%20Wall%20Denver.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ochre Stacked Stone Dividing Wall in Architecture Firm office Denver&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;White and grey stone is easy to contrast, but the multi color blend of our Ochre Rock Panels can pose more a design challenge in terms of selecting the right flooring color.  This architect’s office in Denver, CO selected a deep brown carpet which really pulls out the “earth” tones of the Ochre color and is a nice backdrop for the lighter rust and rose colored accents that are part of the blend.  The unique carpet border around this partial wall which separates two spaces in the firm’s lobby also helps to create that division through the use of contrasting color with the lighter carpet abutting it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/07/12/Basalt%203D%20Ash%20Grey%20Bathroom%20Feature%20Wall%20Dallas-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Luxury Modern Master bathroom with marble floors and honed grey stone veneer wall in Dallas&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More subtle contrast can be found in this next project, both in terms of color and material selection.  The darkest parts of the polished white / grey marble floor are basically the same color as the Grey Basalt 3D accent wall in this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-bathrooms-designing-norstone-series/&quot;&gt;exquisite natural stone master bath&lt;/a&gt; in Dallas, TX.  The use of natural material in this space, from the marble on the floors, basalt on the walls, and even the unique floating wood tub surround all complement each other without the need to contrast against a man-made or synthetic material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/07/12/Basalt%20Interlocking%20Ash%20Grey%20San%20Francisco%20Patio.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;City Backyard in San Francisco featuring artificial turf and a grey interlocking tile feature wall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our last featured space reminds us to think &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/outside-the-box-stone-design-ideas-for-your-next-remodel-or-new-build/&quot;&gt;outside the box when it comes to your flooring options&lt;/a&gt;.  It would have been so easy to use any sort of grey cement or stone paver or similar hardscape product in this unique San Francisco “city backyard”, but the use of artificial turf makes this space far more inviting and memorable.  The lush green color considerably brightens up the area and gives it an outside feel, and the plush texture is a nice foil to the smooth honed finish of the Grey Basalt Interlocking Tile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for taking a look at some of our favorite projects and how flooring can really add to the overall look of a space where stacked stone veneer has been used.  We’d love to see photos of the flooring our readers used with their projects, or if you’re considering what kind of flooring to use on your next stacked stone project, let our design team guide your way and reach out to us today.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">You've designed and maybe already installed an amazing stone wall, now use these tips to make sure the flooring in the space is just as on point as the wall you can't keep your eyes off of.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2017/07/12/Basalt%203D%20Ash%20Grey%20Bathroom%20Feature%20Wall%20Dallas.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Flooring%20to%20Match%20a%20Stone%20Veneer%20Wall%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Modern%20luxury%20bathroom%20featuring%20complimentary%20light%20grey%20polished%20marble%20flooring%20and%20grey%20honed%20stone%20veneer%20wall.%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Modern Stacked Stone Masterpiece in Asheville, NC</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/modern-stacked-stone-masterpiece-in-asheville-nc/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Modern Stacked Stone Masterpiece in Asheville, NC" /><published>2017-07-07T10:12:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-07-07T10:12:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/modern-stacked-stone-masterpiece-in-asheville-nc</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/modern-stacked-stone-masterpiece-in-asheville-nc/">&lt;p&gt;Having never visited Asheville, NC, the team at Norstone had a preconceived notion that most of the high end architecture in the area was “Southern Grand” in line with the famous Gilded era Biltmore Estate, one of the areas biggest tourist destinations.  There’s no doubt that Southern Revival Architecture has a place in this pocket of the North Carolina’s Blueridge mountains, but what really took us by surprise was this Modern Masterpiece of a home that a designer client of ours completed recently that would fit right in if its was located in Miami Beach or the Hollywood Hills.  Let’s take a look at how the our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/thin-stone-veneer-panels/charcoal/&quot;&gt;Charcoal XL Stacked Stone Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt; were used to set this project apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/07/07/Modern%20Stacked%20Stone%20Patio%20Asheville.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Modern Stacked Stone Patio in Asheville, NC&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The modern design of this home is most evident in the low pitched roof lines and overall clean lines of the space.  Extensive use of brushed stainless on the soffitt and trim work contrast nicely with the color and texture of the Charcoal XL stone veneer used on twin accent walls coming out from the interior of the home and terminating on the rear patio.  A massive fold up glass partition wall allows for the interior and exterior spaces to come together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/07/07/Modern%20Stacked%20Stone%20Flagstone%20Patio%20Asheville.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Modern Stacked Stone Flagstone Patio in Asheville, NC&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An extended &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-patios-designing-norstone-series/&quot;&gt;natural stone patio&lt;/a&gt; of various size and patterned square and rectangle pavers is a unique and interesting design choice.  The size and shape are clearly meant to tie back to the clean lines and sharp corners of the home, yet the irregular spacing and mixed in landscaping allow a nice transition from the modern feel of the home to the beautiful nature and lake views this property calls home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/07/07/Modern%20Stacked%20Stone%20Fireplace%20Asheville.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Modern Stacked Stone Fireplace in Asheville, NC&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The view, not only of the amazing corner stone fireplace and large stacked stone accent wall, but also of the lakefront takes center stage when inside the home.  The fireplace is quite unique and one of the most “built in” designs we’ve ever seen.  The attention to detail used to create this cantilevered corner fireplace, including the use of a continuous stone slab for both the firebox and continuing on along the entire media wall, as well as the absence of any glass partition between the room and gas flame makes this unit and the stone wall around it a work of art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/07/07/Modern%20Stacked%20Stone%20Feature%20Wall%20Asheville.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Modern Stacked Stone Feature Wall in Asheville, NC&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stacked stone on opposing walls of this main living space creates a great contrast in texture that is often overlooked in modern design and helps direct focus towards the large glass wall and out beyond to the lake.  While natural light is in abundance in the space, the thoughtful use of up and down &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-school-pairing-lighting-fixtures-with-stone-veneer-for-amazing-results/&quot;&gt;lighting on this stone accent wall&lt;/a&gt; will give the room a lot of character in the evening hours that would have been lost without the lighting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/07/07/Modern%20Stacked%20Stone%20Pool%20Asheville.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Modern Stacked Stone Pool in Asheville,NC&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not to be overlooked is the small yet packed with features &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/summer-s-here-jump-into-these-amazing-pools-designed-with-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;stone lined relaxation pool&lt;/a&gt;.  This little space has it all – an infinity edge overlooking the lake, built in stepping stones that allow access to and from an isolated section of the rear patio, and a cool stacked stone accent wall with a large cut out to walk through.  What this pool lacks in size it more than makes up for in cutting edge design and features that flow perfectly into the rest of the outdoor space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here at Norstone, we’re fans of all different types of architecture and design, and we have products suitable for all styles and inspirations.  Our Charcoal XL panels were a great choice for the modern aesthetic of this project, but a very closely related product, our Ochre XL panel, while using the same sizing and design, pairs well with a much more rustic design scheme.  We have in house design experts ready to discuss your project and recommend products given your style.  Contact us today to start the process of using natural stone veneer and tile on your next job!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">We're incredibly impressed with the use of our Charcoal XL Stacked Stone veneer on this new construction modern lake home in Asheville, NC. Take a seat and let's look at some of the design features that make this project award worthy.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2017/07/07/Asheville%20NC%20Modern%20Stacked%20Stone%20Home.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Asheville%20NC%20Modern%20Stacked%20Stone%20Home%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Asheville%20NC%20Modern%20Stacked%20Stone%20Home%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Selecting the Right Installer for your Next Tile or Stone Project</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/selecting-the-right-installer-for-your-next-tile-or-stone-project/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Selecting the Right Installer for your Next Tile or Stone Project" /><published>2017-06-30T14:46:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-06-30T14:46:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/selecting-the-right-installer-for-your-next-tile-or-stone-project</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/selecting-the-right-installer-for-your-next-tile-or-stone-project/">&lt;p&gt;While all of our products are extremely &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-diy-infographic/&quot;&gt;DIY friendly&lt;/a&gt; and their installation can be mastered by most handy homeowners with minimal experience, we find that an increasing majority of our clients are looking to have professionals install their stone and tile.  For most, life is so busy that they put a lot of value on the time an installation would take, not to mention a job well done.  To ensure that job is indeed done well, we’ve put together a checklist to use to make sure you’re hiring the right installer for your next tile or stone project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;make-sure-youre-hiring-the-right-type-of-contractor&quot;&gt;Make sure you’re hiring the right type of contractor&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/30/Planter%20Box%20Stacked%20Stone%20Installation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;White Stacked Stone being installed on a curved planter box&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the often overlooked steps in finding the right installer for your next tile or stone project is actually making sure you’ve got the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/hiring-a-contractor-for-your-next-stone-project/&quot;&gt;right type of contractor for the job.&lt;/a&gt;  A lot of time stone projects create confusion because many clients think they should be working with a stone mason, when in fact the product might be made out of stone, but is installed like a tile, such as our Norstone Stacked Stone Rock Panels.  When in doubt, the manufacturer of the tile and stone product, or the reputable wholesaler or retailer that you are purchasing the material from should be able to recommend the right type of contractor to do the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;start-the-search-by-asking-your-network&quot;&gt;Start the search by asking your network&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/30/Houzz%20Header.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Screnshot of the header of the Houzz website&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In today’s world, the logical place to start asking for referrals for a quality installer is in both your online and offline social networks.  If that search bears little fruit, the design community Houzz is another great option to find qualified installers in your local area, and view the reviews that have been written about them and their work on the community.  If the tile or stone product is being purchased locally, the local wholesaler or retailer may or may not offer installation services, but certainly should be able to give you a few referrals to contractors reputable in the area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;qualify-the-installer-for-the-work&quot;&gt;Qualify the installer for the work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/30/Commercial%20Charcoal%20Stone%20Veneer%20Installers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Installers working on a commercial stone veneer installation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When interviewing a contractor for the project its important to qualify them as having the skills for the type of work involved.  If you’re working on a mosaic glass tile backsplash, ask them about their experience installing glass tile, and what kind of tools they have at their disposal for this type of installation.  Similarly, if your project involves natural stone tile, make sure the installer has worked with natural stone before.  Another great differentiatior among installers is going to be industry certifications.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/learning-the-best-practices-for-tile-and-stone-installations-by-the-tile-council-of-north-america/&quot;&gt;Certified Tile Installers&lt;/a&gt;, as tested and awarded by governing bodies like the Tile Council of North America, are almost always going to offer a superior installation leveraging the techniques learned during the certification process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-references&quot;&gt;Get References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Request and speak to as many references as possible provided by the installers you are considering.  Learn what kind of work the installer did for them and how long ago the work was completed.  Ask the references if there were any issues, big or small, before, during, or after installation and how the installer worked with them to resolve them.  Be wary of references that are dated or none of the references noted any kind of issues with the process and don’t be afraid to ask for more references.  Installers that do good work have great references, so if something doesn’t feel right with an installer’s references, definitely take that into consideration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-all-of-the-details-in-writing&quot;&gt;Get all of the details in writing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve selected an installer, get all the details in some form of written communication.  Email and text messaging is most common these days for smaller projects.  Formal contracts and / or service agreements should be expected for larger projects.  Use this an opportunity to make it clear about what the contractor is responsible for doing and what you, the client, are responsible for.  Things like substrate preparation and setting materials might vary from job to job, installer to installer, so make sure its clear before you get started.  Other details like payment schedule and warranty expectations should not be overlooked either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;make-yourself-available-during-the-installation&quot;&gt;Make yourself available during the installation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/30/DIY%20Bathtastic%20Stone%20Feature%20Wall-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Norstone Ochre Stacked Stone Rock Panel Installation on DIY show Bathtastic&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s always a good idea to make yourself, or someone you trust to make decisions for you, available and present during the installation.  Very few professional installers enjoy a client hanging over them all the time, but checking in at the beginning of each day to make sure they have everything they need and any questions answered, as well as stopping in at various points throughout the day is a great way to build trust with your installer and ensure a successful outcome.  Use these visits to not only survey the work that’s already been done, but primarily to look ahead at where the install is going and cover any unique situations, like what type of corner trim should be used in a certain spot, or how the tile is going to be cut around an outlet cover to avoid having to rework any of those tricky spots later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;be-an-enthusiastic-reference&quot;&gt;Be an enthusiastic reference&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your installer did a great job and you’re satisfied with the work, let them know it!  If they are active on social media networks, especially Houzz, write a glowing review, or offer up your name and number to serve as a reference for future clients.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Making sure you've got the right installer for a tile or stone project is one of the most important parts of the whole job. Here's a deep dive into the steps you should be taking when finding your next tile or stone installer.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2017/06/30/DIY%20Bathtastic%20Stone%20Feature%20Wall.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22How%20to%20Pick%20The%20Right%20Installer%20for%20a%20Tile%20Project%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22An%20installer%20setting%20stone%20veneer%20in%20a%20bathroom%20feature%20wall%20%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Amazing Interior &amp;amp; Exterior Palm Beach Remodel</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/amazing-interior-exterior-palm-beach-remodel/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Amazing Interior &amp; Exterior Palm Beach Remodel" /><published>2017-06-26T17:24:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-06-26T17:24:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/amazing-interior-exterior-palm-beach-remodel</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/amazing-interior-exterior-palm-beach-remodel/">&lt;p&gt;When the photos of this recently completed remodel in Palm Beach, FL came across our desk we were excited to share them with our network and talk in a little more detail about some of the subtle things that make this project amazing.  This project is particularly compelling because they were able to use the stone in both &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/interiors/&quot;&gt;interior&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/exteriors/&quot;&gt;exterior applications&lt;/a&gt;, creating that consistent color pallet and design aesthetic throughout the entire space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/26/Ochre%20-%20Residential%20-%20Palm%20Beach%20-%20Exterior%201.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ochre Stacked Stone on Residential Garage in Palm Beach&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting on the street facing exterior, the Ochre Rock Panel is cleverly used on the detached garage.  The garage is quite large by itself with 3 wide stalls, two of which are covered with the stone, which then extends out towards the street in a smaller but still rectangular overhang, creating the illusion of a larger garage, and also doing a good job of creating depth on a home that is set far back from the street.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/26/Ochre%20-%20Residential%20-%20Palm%20Beach%20-%20Exterior%202.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ochre Stacked Stone on breezeway in Palm Beach&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next thing that really catches our eye is the fantastic use of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stone-veneer-columns-norstone-classroom-series/&quot;&gt;corner units used on the columns&lt;/a&gt; of the breezeway which connects the garage and the house.  Norstone’s exclusive finger joint method corners really shine through in a detail like this where a natural looking corner is required.  Outside we also love the color match between the stone and the acid stained concrete driveway, as well as the mid century modern looking cut flagstone used on the entryway and steps.  A subtle detail on the exterior not to be missed is the stone veneer used as an accent below the upper windows creating that consistent exterior look between the garage, breezeway, and main house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/26/Ochre%20-%20Residential%20-%20Palm%20Beach%20-%20Feature%20Wall%201-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ochre Stone Veneer Floor to Ceiling Feature Wall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the interior, a blade wall bisects the main house in half longways and is covered floor to vaulted ceiling in stacked stone.  When the design trend is to often go dark with wood flooring, we love this client’s choice of going light on the floors, post and beam work, as well as the expansive paneled ceiling.  Along with the great natural light in this area, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-color-series-designing-ochre-blend/&quot;&gt;lighter tones of our Ochre Blend&lt;/a&gt; really shine through giving the living area a vibrant feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/26/Ochre%20-%20Residential%20-%20Palm%20Beach%20-%20Feature%20Wall%202.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ochre Stacked Stone Feature Wall with built in bookshelves&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The liberal use of built in shelving and niches in the blade wall is an artistic detail that should not go unnoticed.  The crafty use of various sizes and locations all with very geometric shapes goes along with the windows, doors, and hallways complimenting the linear geometry of the stacked stone panel system.  The consistency of a thin veneer panel system really shines through where a more traditional hand stacked loose veneer installation would end up looking less linear against the clean lines of the openings and breaks in the wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/26/Ochre%20-%20Residential%20-%20Palm%20Beach%20-%20Feature%20Wall%203.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ochre Exterior Columns on Patio in Palm Beach&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stone makes a final appearance &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-patios-designing-norstone-series/&quot;&gt;cladding the exterior columns on the back patio&lt;/a&gt;, an essential extension of any home in Florida. We love the way the subtle uplighting is tastefully done on the columns and the continued use of corner units on so many key areas, including the main entrance hallway into the living space, looks the best a corner possibly can using thin veneer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From start to finish this project’s consistent use of the Ochre Blend Rock Panel veneer does a great job of creating a cohesive look whether you’re out front parking the car, cooking dinner, or enjoying a balmy South Florida summer evening on the patio with a chilled drink in hand.  One of the great things about Norstone products is that they can be used both interior and exterior and more importantly, look great in either type of application.  Many exterior stone products look a little rough around the edges when used on the confines of an interior application, while some interior products shouldn’t even be used outside.  With a product like Norstone you can  focus on the overall design and create spaces that are truly interconnected like this amazing project we’ve happily shared with you.  Don’t hesitate to contact Norstone today to discuss your next project and how our unique and exclusive natural stone veneer products can be a part of it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">At Norstone we're love great architecture, and this recently remodeled contemporary home in Palm Beach, FL checks all the boxes. Let's take a look at what makes this project where Norstone was used in both interior and exterior applications so special.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2017/06/26/Ochre%20-%20Residential%20-%20Palm%20Beach%20-%20Feature%20Wall%201.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Luxury%20Palm%20Beach%20Contemporary%20Remodel%20Stone%20Blade%20Wall%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Blade%20wall%20in%20a%20luxury%20Palm%20Beach%20contemporary%20home%20using%20Norstone%20Ochre%20Blend%20Rock%20Panels%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Learning the Best Practices for Tile and Stone Installations from the Tile Council of North America</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/learning-the-best-practices-for-tile-and-stone-installations-by-the-tile-council-of-north-america/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning the Best Practices for Tile and Stone Installations from the Tile Council of North America" /><published>2017-06-23T16:13:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-06-23T16:13:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/learning-the-best-practices-for-tile-and-stone-installations-by-the-tile-council-of-north-america</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/learning-the-best-practices-for-tile-and-stone-installations-by-the-tile-council-of-north-america/">&lt;p&gt;One of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/what-makes-norstone-different-a-lot/&quot;&gt;things about Norstone that makes our products unique&lt;/a&gt; from other veneers is that we really see and sell the product as a precision tile, as opposed to a more traditional masonry product.  Traditional masonry involves taking relatively basic inputs, like plain cut stone and mortar, and leveraging the talents of the installer to create something beautiful on a wall.  We leverage our ability to produce this same look, but in a thin panel format, which allows the product to be installed by a tile setter in lieu of a stone mason.  So we’re always interested in learning more about how tile is installed and common mistakes made installing tile so we can pass this information on to our clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This past week one of our distribution partners in South Florida was hosting a series of workshops during the evening hours where they invited an educator from the Tile Council of North America to come and speak to their customers, who are primarily tile contractors, about the right and wrong way to be installing tile.  During these workshops the TCNA also promoted their certification program which allows an installer to become a TCNA certified installer.  Here’s a quick highlight of some of the main topics covered in these workshops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/23/Tile%20Council%20of%20North%20America%20Logo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tile Council of North America Logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinset Coverage:  The amount of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/what-is-the-difference-between-different-types-of-thinset-and-what-s-the-best-thinset-for-stacked-stone-installations/&quot;&gt;tile thinset&lt;/a&gt; coverage that an installer gets on the back of a tile is one of the critical components of a quality installation.  The size of the trowel notch relative to the size of the tile and the way the thinset is troweled in straight lines and not swirls all contribute to making sure the back of the tile has adequate thinset coverage.  For a natural stone tile product like Norstone, the TCNA recommends 95% coverage, which is why its so important to follow our recommended installation practice of back buttering each panel and using a 1/2” square notch when installing.  Insufficient coverage can lead to the failure of the installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/23/Tile%20Thinset%20Coverage-min.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Tile with good thinset coverage on the back&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expansion Joints: During the workshop the TCNA educator did a great demonstration showing how the expansion of a tile or surrounding substrate by as a little as the width of a penny can cause tiles to buckle.  Norstone recommends perimeter expansion joints in all installations to ensure that as the installation, including the stone, substrate, and wall system, expand and contract according to the local environmental conditions, everything stays stable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/23/Tile%20Expansion%20Joint%20Failure-min.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tiles that have buckled due to lack of an expansion joint&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installer’s Responsibilities: A key takeaway the TCNA wanted to stress to the installers in the audience was that if the tile installation failed, even if the tile installer did everything correctly, it is still going to be the tile installers problem to handle.  For example, if a homeowner insists on not having a perimeter expansion joint because they want a tight look of tile against wall or floor, and the installation ends up failing, it looks bad on the installer.  Or if the framer on a job framed out a shower using treated wood, which contains moisture and will expand / contract over time, instead of regular kiln dried wood, the installation might fail and again the tile installer looks bad.  The TCNA stresses that its important for all tile installers to make sure every component of their installations are done correctly because as the finishing surface the first thing people will assume was done wrong on a failed installation is the tile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certified Installers:  One of the more interesting industry level topics coming out of this week’s workshops was the concept that the industry is shifting and starting to put a premium on certified installers.  The process is starting at the specification level, where architects and designers that are are choosing what products get used on their projects, are beginning to include in the specification document that the installer must be certified.  Specifiers have long recommended that the product be installed by a “professional” tile setter, but with the added nuance of that professional being “certified” only serves to increase the value of the certification to installers and is something to look for when &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/hiring-a-contractor-for-your-next-stone-project/&quot;&gt;hiring a contractor for your next stone or tile job&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/23/Certified%20Tile%20Installer%20Logo-min.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Certifiled Tile Installer Logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike many of our peers in the industry, the background of the leadership team at Norstone doesn’t include any professional “bucket and trowel” experience, however that hasn’t stopped us from vigorously learning and consulting with industry leaders over the past decade to develop the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/how-to-install-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;best practices for installing Norstone products&lt;/a&gt;.  This week’s TCNA workshops were a great reminder that while it could seem simple on the surface, installing tile is much more than it seems and a wide ranging variety of factors need to be taken into consideration when doing so.  So whether you have questions about a Norstone installation you have planned for the future, or are in the middle of one right now, don’t hesitate to contact us and speak with our technical service team or email us your question and we’ll get back with you right away.  Until then – happy tiling!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2017/06/23/NTCA%20Tile%20Presentation-min.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22NTCA%20Tile%20Installation%20Workshop%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22NTCA%20Tile%20Instatllation%20Workshop%20at%20D&amp;B%20Tile%20in%20South%20Florida%20%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">White Rock Panels in a Stunning Chef’s Kitchen in Suburban Virginia</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/white-rock-panels-in-a-stunning-chef-s-kitchen-in-suburban-virginia/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="White Rock Panels in a Stunning Chef's Kitchen in Suburban Virginia" /><published>2017-06-05T09:06:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-06-05T09:06:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/white-rock-panels-in-a-stunning-chef-s-kitchen-in-suburban-virginia</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/white-rock-panels-in-a-stunning-chef-s-kitchen-in-suburban-virginia/">&lt;p&gt;A couple years ago we got the opportunity to supply white rock panels to this project about 30 miles outside of Washington, DC in suburban Virginia.  Working directly with an engaged homeowner, we weren’t quite sure how stunning this combination backsplash, two sided fireplace and family room accent wall project was going to be until we saw photos of it and were blown away.  Let’s take a look at how the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/rock-panels/white/&quot;&gt;white quartz rock stacked stone rock panels&lt;/a&gt; are subtly used throughout this high end space and how along with the stone, the other high end finishes come together to create a magazine worthy profile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project precipitated out of a kitchen remodel and the search for a unique &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/designing-norstone-series-natural-stone-backsplashes/&quot;&gt;natural stone backsplash&lt;/a&gt; material.  One of the unique things about this project ends up being the backsplash as the homeowners have decided to take the stacked stone tile all the way form the countertop to the ceiling, including the space above the upper cabinets.  This creates a consistent look since the entire wall space is one material, texture, and color, and is also beautifully highlighted by LED lighting, aimed down from the lower cabinets and up from the upper cabinets, as well as down from the ceiling.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-school-pairing-lighting-fixtures-with-stone-veneer-for-amazing-results/&quot;&gt;A great design never overlooks lighting&lt;/a&gt;, especially on a backsplash, as the spaces can get dark from the natural shadow effect of the upper cabinets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/05/White%20Stacked%20Stone%20Backsplash%20in%20Virginia.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;White Stacked Stone Backsplash in Virginia&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 1rem;&quot;&gt;The other design element thoughtfully tied to the backsplash height is the beautiful stainless steel range  hood.  Unique in its positioning in the center of the room over the island range, this well proportioned hood naturally draws the eyes up making it important to design the entire wall, including the oft neglected space between the upper cabinets and ceiling.  Completed a handful of years ago, this project was also one of the first projects we saw boldly mix up cabinet colors and counter top types between the wall and island, something now more prevalent in upscale kitchen design.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/05/White%20Stacked%20Stone%20Fireplace%20Kitchen.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;White Stacked Stone Fireplace Kitchen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 1rem;&quot;&gt;Our favorite part of this space is the two sided fireplace, separating the kitchen and more formal living room.  Choosing to keep the fireplace as part of the renovation, the white stacked stone veneer became a logical option for this feature and helps keep the materials consistent across the space.  Two sided fireplaces are installations where Norstone Rock Panels really shine, especially when our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-classroom-session-working-corners-1/&quot;&gt;industry leading corner units&lt;/a&gt; are involved like in this example, creating a seamless look at and around the outside corners.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/05/White%20Stacked%20Stone%20Fireplace%20Living%20Room.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;White Stacked Stone Firepace Living Room&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The view of the white stacked stone fireplace from the living room is particularly well thought out with the white stone backsplash showing up in the background creating a layered effect of textures throughout the space.  In what could have been just a regular load bearing wall, this two sided fireplace does a great job serving as the focal point of the formal living room and a really unique feature for a kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/05/White%20Stacked%20Stone%20Accent%20Wall%20in%20Virginia.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;White Stacked Stone Accent Wall in Virginia&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real surprise of this project comes on the opposite side of the kitchen, where a casual family room gets a big upgrade with the stacked stone feature wall.  We love the geometry and symmetry of this well, with the two square windows and flanking the low profile television stand , all backed up by the clean lines and texture of the white stone veneer accent wall.  With sightlines including the two big walls of the kitchen backsplash, this feature wall completes a unified theme among the three rooms featured in this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project is a great example of how a common design theme or element, whether its stacked stone or any other finish or color, can be thoughtfully used in various applications and spaces to create amazing spaces.  If you’re stuck on how to get started with your next stacked stone project our entire customer support team has both formal and on the job design experience, so take some photos and give us a call and we’ll get started.  Until then, continue to check back with our blog for more project features and interesting and informative articles on the world of stacked stone and natural stone tile.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Come take a look at this amazing gourmet kitchen featuring Norstone White Rock Panels in countertop to ceiling backsplash and a unique dual sides fireplace that makes this space truly one of a kind.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2017/06/05/White%20Stacked%20Stone%20Backsplash%20with%20Large%20Kitchen%20Island.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22White%20Stacked%20Stone%20Backsplash%20in%20Remodeled%20Virginia%20Kitchen%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Countertop%20to%20ceiling%20white%20stacked%20stone%20backsplash%20in%20a%20remodeled%20kitchen%20with%20large%20island%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Summer’s here! Jump into these Amazing Pools Designed with Stacked Stone</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/summer-s-here-jump-into-these-amazing-pools-designed-with-stacked-stone/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Summer's here! Jump into these Amazing Pools Designed with Stacked Stone" /><published>2017-06-02T14:28:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-06-02T14:28:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/summer-s-here-jump-into-these-amazing-pools-designed-with-stacked-stone</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/summer-s-here-jump-into-these-amazing-pools-designed-with-stacked-stone/">&lt;p&gt;With Memorial Day happening earlier this week, the beginning of summer is officially here, and with the higher temperatures we thought it would be a good idea to take a look at using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/pools/&quot;&gt;stacked stone products in swimming pools.&lt;/a&gt;  Over the years our customers have designed a variety of pools using our stone on everything from raised beams to waterline tiles so let’s take a look at some of our favorites and learn some of the ways &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-industry-series-what-is-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;stacked stone panels&lt;/a&gt; can be used in pools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/02/Ochre%20Stacked%20Stone%20Sheer%20Waterfall%20Pool%20Feature.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ochre Stacked Stone Sheer Waterfall Pool Feature&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most common way we see stacked stone used in pools is on a raised beam application.  A raised beam is essentially a part of the pool shell that extends up and over the level of the deck, forming a focal point.  Depending on the size of the pool and space that it fits in, the beam can be as short as a foot or two to well over head in height if the structure is to be used as a visual screen as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/02/Ochre%20Stacked%20Stone%20Raised%20Beam%20Water%20Feature%20in%20Pool.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Ochre Stacked Stone Raised Beam Water Feature in Pool&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stacked stone is an excellent option for raised beams as it creates great contrast in terms of texture with the water and also brings the natural element of stone into the design.  Often times the raised beam will feature multiple heights and frequently will be paired with a water feature such as a waterfall, water bowl, or scupper to enhance the design with free flowing water coming over, through, or in front of the stone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/02/Ochre%20Stacked%20Stone%20Submerged%20Tile%20in%20Pool.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ochre Stacked Stone Submerged Tile in Pool&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/what-makes-norstone-different-a-lot/&quot;&gt;makes Norstone Rock Panels unique&lt;/a&gt; in the stacked stone veneer marketplace is that we primarily source quartz stone to be used in the manufacturing process.  Quartz is a much harder stone than &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/slate-tile-norstone-classroom-series/&quot;&gt;slate&lt;/a&gt; and sandstone that might be found in lower quality veneer panels which also means that the stacked stone can be used at or below the waterline for a fully or partially submerged application.  In the pool features seen here, the design is really enhanced by the stone’s ability to drop right down into the water and serve as either a waterline or fully submerged stacked stone tile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/02/Charcoal%20Stacked%20Stone%20Infinity%20Edge%20Ledge%20Pool.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Charcoal Stacked Stone Infinity Edge Ledge Pool&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Infinity edge pools are incredibly popular in trending swimming pool design, and stacked stone makes a great option for the spillway.  The water can be designed to spill over a ledge and stay in front of the stone or be directed right onto the face of the stone to create more of a trickling effect that takes advantage of the textured surface the stacked stone creates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/02/Ochre%20Stacked%20Stone%20Infinity%20Edge%20Ledge%20Pool.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ochre Stacked Stone Infinity Edge Ledge Pool&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An important thing to remember about using any type of natural stone and even some types of manmade tile in pools is that not all products are suitable for this environment.  While they are meant primarily for relaxation, pools are a harsh environment for the products that comprise them.  Being subject to constant moisture and chemicals, as well as varying seasons, really puts products to the test.  Many of our stacked stone products and basalt tile products are ideal for your next stone inspired pool design, but be sure to check with a Norstone rep for any specifics that you should know prior to installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you’re considering stacked stone for your next pool project, contact us today and we’ll help you make a BIG SPLASH with stacked stone.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Stacked stone can be used in a variety of features on a swimming pool to enhance the look,texture, and overall design of the space. Explore and learn more about designing pools with stacked stone in mind in this week's featured post.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2017/06/02/Ochre%20Stacked%20Stone%20Waterline%20Tile%20in%20Pool.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Stacked%20Stone%20on%20Pool%20Raised%20Beam%20with%20Waterfall%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Stacked%20Stone%20on%20a%20raised%20beam%20in%20a%20pool%20with%20two%20fire%20bowls%20and%20a%20waterfall%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">An Ivory Comeback for the Summer of 2017</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/an-ivory-comeback-for-the-summer-of-2017/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An Ivory Comeback for the Summer of 2017" /><published>2017-05-23T11:58:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-23T11:58:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/an-ivory-comeback-for-the-summer-of-2017</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/an-ivory-comeback-for-the-summer-of-2017/">&lt;p&gt;Long a favorite of the Norstone team, our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/rock-panels/ivory/&quot;&gt;Ivory Blend&lt;/a&gt; color, which we have available in both our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/stacked-stone-cladding/&quot;&gt;Standard Series&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/thin-stone-veneer-panels/&quot;&gt;XL Series Rock Panels&lt;/a&gt;, was on the opposite side of the recent “grey” color trend dominating neutral design colors of the past couple years.  We’ve always described the Ivory as a “blended” color with ranges from whites / off whites, to creams / ivories, and including some yellows and golds.  We’ve been pleasantly surprised to hear from many clients during the Spring and early Summer months of 2017 on a renewed interest in this color with many projects already installed or in various stages of design and construction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About two years ago, we got the opportunity to view and photograph a residential project in Southwest Florida that masterfully used our Ivory Standard Series Rock Panel on the exterior facade, both front and rear, on a new construction project.  Let’s take a look at how stacked stone was used on this project and what makes it so special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/05/23/Ivory%20Stone%20Veneer%20-%20Fort%20Myers%20%20-%20Facade.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ivory Stacked Stone Veneer on Exterior Residential Facade&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The front facade of this project features multiple columns where the outside corner unit worked perfectly to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/stone-veneer-columns-norstone-classroom-series/&quot;&gt;wrap the columns in stone&lt;/a&gt;.  The entry way, which is strategically set further back from the street than the adjoining garage and opposite wing of the home, becomes the focal point of the exterior facade with the 1.5 story columns covered in stone taking center stage.  Smaller columns placed around the garage and other exterior parts of the home create a cohesive use of the stone.  An overall neutral color palette used on the smooth face stucco, trim, and metal roof complement the light color blend of the Ivory Rock Panel, and also serve as a great base for the window, door, and lighting fixture accents to pop off against.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/05/23/Ivory%20Stone%20Veneer%20-%20Fort%20Myers%20-%20Pool%20Feature.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ivory Stacked Stone Veneer Pool Waterline Tile&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming around to the rear of the house, the design team on this project also used the stone on a short accent wall on the pool deck as well as around a planter that dips down into the pool.  Since the Ivory color is a quartz based stone it is suitable to be used in wet and submerged environments, like the waterline tile seen here.  The light blended color range of Ivory also pairs extremely well with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/travertine-tiles-norstone-designer-series/&quot;&gt;travertine pavers and coping&lt;/a&gt;.  The short accent wall in the background might be a little hard to notice at first, but is worth taking note of because the space is incredibly well designed.  The skinny bamboo plantings do a great job of not blocking the stone at the lower level, and filling out and covering up the boring stucco wall above it.  The subtle up lighting makes sure the stacked stone accent wall stays within view even at nighttime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/05/23/Ivory%20Stone%20Veneer%20-%20Fort%20Myers%20%20-%20Outdoor%20Area-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ivory Stacked Stone Outdoor Living Space with fireplace and curved walls&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The showpiece of this home is most certainly this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/natural-stone-patios-designing-norstone-series/&quot;&gt;outdoor living space&lt;/a&gt;.  We love the subtle curves of the fireplace and bench seating areas as well as the overall color scheme, pairing the Ivory with gold and brown tones and the occasional orange and blue accent.  The curved stone work creates a great contrast with the normal flat look of stacked stone and this space embodies what a luxury outdoor living space should be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve got a stacked stone project to do this summer and are a little bored with the grey and black color range, our advice is to give Ivory a try.  We look forward to seeing what projects our customers complete during the Spring and Summer of 2017 and hope a few of you give Ivory a try!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Color trends come and go, and one that we've noticed recently is a renewed interest in our Ivory Blend color, so we decided to feature a residential project in Southwest Florida that used our Ivory Blend on the exterior as this week's featured project.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2017/05/23/Ivory%20Stone%20Veneer%20-%20Fort%20Myers%20%20-%20Outdoor%20Area.png%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Residential%20Ivory%20Stacked%20Stone%20Outdoor%20Living%20Space%20in%20Fort%20Myers,%20FL%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Residential%20Outdoor%20Living%20Space%20in%20Fort%20Myers,%20FL%20using%20Ivory%20Stacked%20Stone%20on%20a%20fireplace%20and%20curved%20walls%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Install a Flat Screen TV on a Stacked Stone Wall</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-install-a-flat-screen-tv-on-a-stacked-stone-wall/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Install a Flat Screen TV on a Stacked Stone Wall" /><published>2017-05-17T13:10:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-17T13:10:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-install-a-flat-screen-tv-on-a-stacked-stone-wall</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/how-to-install-a-flat-screen-tv-on-a-stacked-stone-wall/">&lt;p&gt;Over the years many of our customers have completed amazing feature walls using our stacked stone &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/&quot;&gt;rock panel products&lt;/a&gt;, and on quite a few of those feature walls they choose to hang a flat screen TV.  When we first started making our products TVs weren’t flat and definitely didn’t get hung on a wall, but as technology evolved and our customers pushed the design limits of their entertainment space the question about how to hang a flat screen tv on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/norstone-industry-series-what-is-stacked-stone/&quot;&gt;stacked stone wall&lt;/a&gt; was one we needed to answer.  Here’s a quick “how to” guide for hanging a flat screen TV on a stacked stone wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-1-determine-the-scope-of-the-project&quot;&gt;Step 1: Determine the Scope of the Project&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever hanging a TV on a wall you’ll need to consider a few things including the locations of electrical and cable outlets.  Before you install anything it makes sense to understand if any of these services need moved, or perhaps a low voltage chaise installed in your wall cavity to allow for the proper hook ups in the location of the new unit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-2-prepare-the-substrate-for-stacked-stone&quot;&gt;Step 2: Prepare the Substrate for Stacked Stone&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most often this involves covering existing drywall with cement board, or if you are already at open wall studs, the cement board can be directly attached to the studs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/05/17/Flat%20Screen%20TV%20installed%20on%20Stacked%20Stone%20Wall%20-%20Installing%20Cement%20Board.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Flat Screen TV installed on Stacked Stone Wall - Installing Cement Board&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-3-select-the-tv-mount-and-check-for-clearance-on-the-wall&quot;&gt;Step 3: Select the TV Mount and Check for Clearance on the Wall&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wall mounts are readily available now through online retailers or brick and mortar electronic stores.  Be sure to select a mount that is properly sized for the television.  In this step it is also a good idea to check the clearance on your mount against the wall that will soon have stone on it.  Allow for at least 2” of stone and setting bed, and make sure you still have clearance to hang the TV on the mount without issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-4-install-the-tv-mount&quot;&gt;Step 4: Install the TV Mount&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the manufacturer’ directions, install the wall mount directly onto the cement board, making sure the screws being used are of sufficient length to reach into the studs.  Depending on the size of television and spacing of the wall studs, it might be a good idea to attach a few 1”x4”s to the wall, making sure these are firmly anchored into the studs, which will allow you more flexibility to place your mount exactly where you want it and attach it to the 1”x4”s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-5-protect-the-mount-and-install-the-stacked-stone&quot;&gt;Step 5: Protect the Mount and Install the Stacked Stone&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use painters or masking tape and some plastic sheeting to cover up the wall mount during installation of the stacked stone.  Install the stacked stone using a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/what-is-the-difference-between-different-types-of-thinset-and-what-s-the-best-thinset-for-stacked-stone-installations/&quot;&gt;polymer modified thinset &lt;/a&gt;and making the appropriate cuts around the mount.  It’s a good idea to save some extra stone in a closet or attic such that if you ever decide to take the TV down from the wall, you can remove the mount and go back and fill in the gap with stone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/05/17/Flat%20Screen%20TV%20installed%20on%20Stacked%20Stone%20Wall%20-%20Installing%20Stone.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Flat Screen TV installed on Stacked Stone Wall - Installing Stone&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-6-install-the-tv-mount-hang-on-the-wall-and-hook-up-connections&quot;&gt;Step 6: Install the TV Mount, Hang on the Wall and Hook Up Connections&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the stacked stone installation is complete, install the TV side of the wall mount on the TV unit itself and hang the entire unit on the wall.  A couple extra sets of hands can help a lot in this step by helping guide the TV into place and plugging in / managing the cords.  Most wall mounts will make a distinctive click when the unit is secured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-7-clean-up--enjoy&quot;&gt;Step 7: Clean Up &amp;amp; Enjoy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zip ties are a handy tool for managing excess length on any electrical or low voltage cables, so make sure that any excess length is tucked up nice and neat behind the TV. Finally, enjoy your new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/natural-stone-feature-walls/&quot;&gt;stacked stone media wall&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/05/17/Flat%20Screen%20TV%20installed%20on%20Stacked%20Stone%20Wall%20-%20Living%20Room.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Flat Screen TV installed on Stacked Stone Wall - Living Room&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In retrofit situations, where you already have stacked stone on a wall or fireplace and you’re wanting to come back and hang a tv over it, our first recommendation is to always see if a small portion of the stone can be cut or chipped out of the existing installation to create a flat surface to mount the bracket to.  It might be possible with a lot of patience and some sturdy shims to try and drill through the stone, and shim the bracket out on the face of an irregular surface like stacked stone.  If attempting a retrofit installation of that nature, its very important that a direct mechanical bond is made into the wall stud to make sure the TV stays safe on the wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a combined 40+ years experience in the stone industry our technical team is here to answer any questions you might have or troubleshoot anything unique to your project.  Call or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/contact-us/&quot;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt; today!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Stacked stone makes a great backdrop for a media wall and a question we get asked all the time is how to hang a flat screen tv on the stone. Keep reading our latest blog for the best solution to this quandary and some other tips and tricks we point out along the way.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2017/05/17/Flat%20Screen%20TVs%20installed%20on%20Stacked%20Stone%20Wall%20-%20Casino.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Flat%20Screen%20TVs%20installed%20on%20Stacked%20Stone%20Wall%20-%20Casino%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Flat%20Screen%20TVs%20installed%20on%20Stacked%20Stone%20Wall%20in%20a%20Casino%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Study Surrounded by Beauty in this Downtown Philadelphia University Student Housing Lounge</title><link href="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/study-surrounded-by-beauty-in-this-downtown-philadelphia-university-student-housing-lounge/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Study Surrounded by Beauty in this Downtown Philadelphia University Student Housing Lounge" /><published>2017-05-08T14:47:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-08T14:47:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/study-surrounded-by-beauty-in-this-downtown-philadelphia-university-student-housing-lounge</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/study-surrounded-by-beauty-in-this-downtown-philadelphia-university-student-housing-lounge/">&lt;p&gt;The beginning of May brings with it graduations across the country, filled with young people ready to take on the world.  Fond memories of our own university life were relived last fall when the Norstone team visited this cool installation at Drexel University featuring a large &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/gallery/application/fireplace/&quot;&gt;two sided fireplace&lt;/a&gt; adorned with our Ebony Basalt Interlocking Tile.  Having worked extensively with the design firm out of Austin, TX on this project, it was great to see our work come full circle from the initial sampling, design, bidding and construction, to now installed and being used and enjoyed by the students lucky enough to call this housing complex home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/05/08/Ebony%20Basalt%20Interlocking%20Tile%20Drexel%20University%20-%20Lobby%20View.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ebony Basalt Interlocking Tile Drexel University - Lobby View&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Situated in downtown Philadelphia, just across the Schuylkill River from Center City, this recently completed student housing tower feels a lot more like an upscale apartment complex in any major metropolitan area than what many of us would traditionally think of as a dormitory.  With numerous cafes and eateries within walking distance, and a clean exterior facade of glass and stonework, the lobby opens up beyond the check in desk to a lounge area with the two sided &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-trends-when-it-comes-to-stone-smooth-is-in/&quot;&gt;smooth basalt stone&lt;/a&gt; fireplace serving as both a focal point as well as a natural divider of the open space.  It’s hard to pull your eye away from the gas fireplace – at a long and skinny six feet in length this unit puts out a lot of attractive flames, the movement of which automatically becomes the focal point of the entire lobby area.  This space also holds a billiards area with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/blog/design-school-pairing-lighting-fixtures-with-stone-veneer-for-amazing-results/&quot;&gt;modern lighting fixture&lt;/a&gt; and plenty of open seating option to either be social, or put your earbuds in and get some studying done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/05/08/Ebony%20Basalt%20Interlocking%20Tile%20Drexel%20University%20-%20See%20Though%20Fireplace.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ebony Basalt Interlocking Tile Drexel University - See Though Fireplace&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The opposite side of the fireplace is a sunken lounge with conversational style seating.  The design team did a fantastic job of pairing the clean geometric lines of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norstoneusa.com/products/modern-wall-tile/&quot;&gt;basalt interlocking tile&lt;/a&gt; used on the fireplace with modern furniture and linear accents.  From this side, the fireplace is really the focus of the space, and does a great job commanding your attention.  From the unique twin cut outs on either side, to the large TV, to the modern and eye catching linear gas see through fireplace, this project packs a lot of punch in a small area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/05/08/Ebony%20Basalt%20Interlocking%20Tile%20Drexel%20University%20-%20Gas%20Fireplace.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ebony Basalt Interlocking Tile Drexel University - Gas Fireplace&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things we like the most about this product is the subtle texture that it creates on the wall.  This view of the fireplace, taken to show some of the light coming in from the street level floor to ceiling windows shows some of that texture.  This product creates movement with its interlocking pattern, calibrated color variation, and just enough dimensionality to look really outstanding on a wall.  That dimensionality can be hard to detect in a photo, especially taken straight on, which is why we like this image so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/05/08/Ebony%20Basalt%20Interlocking%20Tile%20Drexel%20University%20-%20Bold%20Color%20Accents.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ebony Basalt Interlocking Tile Drexel University - Bold Color Accents&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One final thing that we enjoy about this project is the design team’s liberal stance on using color.  While the dark ebony color of the basalt interlocking tile goes well with the grey wood plank style flooring, and the predominantly grey base color of the walls, the use of in your face colors like the yellow accent wall deep pink pass throughs on either side of the fireplace bring a lot of life to the room.  Designing with those colors can be a challenge in a more conservative residential application, but the temporary and shared aspect of this student housing lounge makes them a perfect foil for the darker tones on the fireplace and flooring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This spring we salute the students who get to call this place home and hope that some of these bright young minds might have seen our tile, gained some inspiration, and will go out and do great things in this world.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rassan Grant</name></author><summary type="html">Norstone Basalt Interlocking Tile is used prominently in the lounge of a student housing complex on the downtown Philadelphia campus of Drexel University. Let's check out what makes this space so well designed and probably much nicer than any dorm we've spent time in.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.norstoneusa.com/%7B%22src%22=%3E%22/uploads/2017/05/08/Ebony%20Basalt%20Interlocking%20Tile%20Drexel%20University%20-%204.jpg%22,%20%22title%22=%3E%22Ebony%20Bassalt%20Interlocking%20Fireplace%20Profile%20-%20Philadelphia%22,%20%22alt%22=%3E%22Ebony%20Bassalt%20Interlocking%20Fireplace%20Profile%20-%20Philadelphia%22%7D" /></entry></feed>